<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>NORIFIX diary</title><lang>ja</lang><link>https://ympbyc.github.io/shortblog/blog/index.html</link><copyright>Copyright (c) norifix</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 21:42:20 +0900</lastBuildDate><generator>shortblog https://github.com/ympbyc/shortblog</generator><item><title>2021-09-08</title><description>(Fixing the flat tyre on S's bike. I can't find the patch so I cut a small patch out of old tube.  Hopefully it sticks. @2021-09-08 21:41
 9/8 Rainy. Gas cutting practice continues.  I got more familier with making the fire by adjusting the amount of acetylene and oxygen.  I'm not afraid of lighting anymore.  It's stillvery thrilling to melt-cut. @2021-09-08 21:40
 9/7 Sunny. ガスカットの練習.アセチレンに10倍の圧力の酸素を混ぜて鉄板やアングル材を溶断する。写真のノズル、一番手前がアセチレンのノブ、親指あたりが酸素、上が高圧酸素。最初は点火が怖い。火花も盛大に散る。ノズルの先端が部材に接触すると、パーンと破裂音がするのでびっくりする。 @2021-09-08 21:35
 9/6 First encounter with gas cutting torch. @2021-09-08 21:25
 FILE: IMGP0016-2021-09-08-21-24.JPG @2021-09-08 21:24
 FILE: IMGP0015-2021-09-08-21-24.JPG @2021-09-08 21:24
 FILE: IMGP0012-2021-09-08-21-23.JPG @2021-09-08 21:23
 FILE: IMGP0010-2021-09-08-21-23.JPG @2021-09-08 21:23
 FILE: IMGP0009-2021-09-08-21-23.JPG @2021-09-08 21:23
 FILE: IMGP0006-2021-09-08-21-23.JPG @2021-09-08 21:23
 FILE: IMGP0004-2021-09-08-21-23.JPG @2021-09-08 21:23
 FILE: IMGP0003-2021-09-08-21-23.JPG @2021-09-08 21:23
 FILE: IMGP0002-2021-09-08-21-23.JPG @2021-09-08 21:23)</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 21:41:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-09-04</title><description>(Went toonsen in the evening and met kanon dad.  He bought me a can of coca-cola. @2021-09-04 22:14
 9/4 Cloudy.  Adopt 北岸. Picked up many trash along the road. talked to nmz, nkli, fjmt couple, ksnk, tthm, etc. @2021-09-04 22:13
 9/3 Sea's birthday. @2021-09-04 22:09
 FILE: IMGP0008-2021-09-04-21-59.JPG @2021-09-04 21:59
 FILE: IMGP0004-2021-09-04-21-59.JPG @2021-09-04 21:59
 FILE: IMGP0003-2021-09-04-21-59.JPG @2021-09-04 21:59)</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2021 22:14:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-09-02</title><description>(FILE: IMGP0002-2021-09-02-22-42.JPG @2021-09-02 22:42
 FILE: IMGP0008-2021-09-02-22-42.JPG @2021-09-02 22:42
 FILE: IMGP0006-2021-09-02-22-42.JPG @2021-09-02 22:42
 FILE: IMGP0004-2021-09-02-22-40.JPG @2021-09-02 22:40
 FILE: IMGP0003-2021-09-02-22-39.JPG @2021-09-02 22:39
 FILE: IMGP0002-2021-09-02-22-39.JPG @2021-09-02 22:39
 Bought a rain jacket + pants at a recycle shop. I also bought a tumbler with rapunzel printed on its side for sea.  Bought a cotton jacket for welding at WORKMAN. @2021-09-02 22:38
 9/2 Rainy. Training starts. Drew product blueprint (on white paper though) with pencil, eraser, compass, and ruler.  I asked the teacher if there's a quicker way to draw parallel lines and he told us a cheat. @2021-09-02 22:35
 9/1 消防団。Fire extinguishing simulation was cancelled and we just drove the firetruck around the villege to promote fire safety. K, K, O @2021-09-02 22:29
 9/1 Sunny. First day at polytech.  I had to sit in a white conference room facing front for hours and fill in papers after papers. In the morning the road is much more conjested than I'm used to.  Going by bike everyday may be stressful. @2021-09-02 22:26
 8/31 Sunny. Elliot and Mayu showed up.  We talked, juggled, and talked. Elliot is very bright and opened many drawers of my mind/life.  I so want to go touring across countries with family on bikes.  I want to try slacklining.  Saba barazushi Satoco cooked was delicious. @2021-09-02 22:22)</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 22:42:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-09-04</title><description>(FILE: IMGP0017-2021-09-04-21-59.JPG @2021-09-04 21:59
 FILE: IMGP0011-2021-09-04-21-58.JPG @2021-09-04 21:58
 FILE: IMGP0010-2021-09-04-21-58.JPG @2021-09-04 21:58)</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2021 21:59:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-08-31</title><description>(便座を和式に変えたい。古いトイレ復活計画。しゃがんだ方が、お腹の圧がすっかり抜けるよう。 @2021-08-31 14:35
 WANT: a sceletium tortuosum seedling. @2021-08-31 10:15)</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 14:35:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-08-30</title><description>(FILE: IMGP0013-2021-08-30-22-57.JPG @2021-08-30 22:57
 FILE: IMGP0012-2021-08-30-22-57.JPG @2021-08-30 22:57
 FILE: IMGP0010-2021-08-30-22-57.JPG @2021-08-30 22:57
 FILE: IMGP0006-2021-08-30-22-56.JPG @2021-08-30 22:56
 FILE: IMGP0005-2021-08-30-22-56.JPG @2021-08-30 22:56
 FILE: IMGP0004-2021-08-30-22-56.JPG @2021-08-30 22:56
 FILE: IMGP0003-2021-08-30-22-56.JPG @2021-08-30 22:56
 FILE: IMGP0001-2021-08-30-22-55.JPG @2021-08-30 22:55
 午後、トレラン。子供15人、大人6+人。自転車で坂を登って黄ミゼットに拾ってもらった。帰りに温泉に寄って帰ってきた。夜ご飯は枝豆とごぼうと鶏ももの炊き込みご飯。美味しい。昼も美味しかった。えごまジェノベーゼ+トマト+エビのペンネ。 @2021-08-30 22:51
 昼、タクシー会社からスイカが半玉届く。会長と雑談。 @2021-08-30 22:47
 朝、近所の建具屋さんから飾りのかぼちゃと桃の種のキーホルダーを貰う。ぶどうを持ってタクシー会社に行ったら、お返しにさざえを3つくれた。焚き火で焼いて食べて美味しかった。コメリから草刈り機が届く。14.4V。早速組み立てて試しに刈ってみる。庭で使うにはパワーは十分。 @2021-08-30 22:44
 8/29 Sぶどう園へ。家事、玄関掃除後、おから米粉クッキーを焼いて子どもたちと川へ。お鶴からのお誘い。行ってみると人が多すぎてぼーっとしてしまったあげく眠すぎて砂利の上で寝た。夕、切り干し大根が美味しくできた。切り干し大根、油揚げ、人参、ピーマン、みりん、出汁醤油、酢少し、梅干1個。夜、岩丸さん誕生日会。ごはんが美味しい。久しぶりに行くと安心した。 @2021-08-30 22:37)</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 22:57:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-08-27</title><description>(Called tsuyoshi-san.  He told me of a job that earns 10000000/year.  I'm slightly interested. @2021-08-27 23:22
 BOOK: METAMAGICAL THEMAS @2021-08-27 23:19
 BOOK:koe no shihonshugi @2021-08-27 23:18
 Couldn't move in the morning and I had to sleep through til 11. Then I cut+pulled weeds in the garden. Then I went to the dentist and got the hole in the upper right teeth filled up w/ resin. S and kids went to Naruto w/ her friend and hunted kai. @2021-08-27 23:15)</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 23:23:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-08-26</title><description>(Went shopping w/ S. Sofa was out of stock. I bought a big saw and a fish net.  We ate indian curry for lunch. Spice felt good in the stomach. @2021-08-26 23:10)</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 23:10:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-08-25</title><description>(ササドジョウの捕り方。網で砂を掬うと入る @2021-08-25 21:42
 Last night I found a mystery joint up on the 神棚. It's a total mystery how old it was. In the evening I brought it to xavier's house and shared it w/ him. @2021-08-25 19:54
 took kids to the river and coincidentally met emma, chiquita, and soyo and kids.  The water was cold.  A car tried to drive into the sand by the river and got stuck. I pushed it back up the slope. 3 girls came out and said thanks. @2021-08-25 19:53
 電気代金5161円、水道代金2ヶ月5430円、マキタ充電刈払機14.4V 19800円、それぞれ振込。 @2021-08-25 19:48
 Ordered an electric bush cutter. @2021-08-25 19:46)</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 21:42:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-08-24</title><description>(FILE: benoit-yue-2021-08-25-19-44.jpg @2021-08-24 19:44
 S called from the city and invited me to come over to the guest house she stayed. I rode the bicycle to the station and met S and kids in the bicycle cafe dancing doll. We walked to the Vacation house YUE only to find out that the house is the same house I visited Benoit and Gerrit during their stay in the city.  :[ ] @2021-08-24 19:40)</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 19:44:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-08-23</title><description>(自転車実験室の準備をした。ブリキの工具缶に部品と工具を詰めただけ。 @2021-08-23 23:40
 酔っ払ってジャグリングをする動画を取るのはやめよう。 @2021-08-23 23:38
 帰り道、いつもはいかないスーパーに行ったら、島根産の穴子の蒲焼きを売っていた。アミノ酸つまり味の素が入っているけど買ってみた。案の定すばらしくケミカルな旨味で口の中がおかしくなった。 @2021-08-23 23:37
 ポリテク近くの脳神経外科へ、血圧測定、握力測定、問診、頭痛チェックシート、うつチェックシート、マルチスライスCTスキャン、医師の所見説明。CTで特に異常は認められない。うつは、15点以上はうつとなるチェックシートで14点でボーダーライン。緊張性頭痛だろうとのこと。投薬は断った。画像診断1470点と初診料で窓口負担5,270円。　CT画像を自分で見た時、頭蓋骨自体に歪みが少しあるように見えた。 @2021-08-23 23:34)</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 23:40:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-08-22</title><description>(I've been having problems w/ my left half of the body and the head + 三叉神経feeling wierd and sickening for a while.  I found MAOI greatly reduce this symptom. I'm considering a visit to a neurologist. @2021-08-22 23:22
 Sunny/Rain-drops Sea practiced riding her bicycle in the morning. In the afternoon I took MAOI and rode the bike with sea and sky in the trailer. After an hour of pedaling we arrive at hanamaru udon. We ate 温玉ぶっかけ, 磯辺揚げ, 厚揚げ, 煮玉子. Then we went to a little park w/ a slide and swings but the rain started dropping. So I parked the bicycle and the trailer under a roof and we went inside the building next to the little park. Inside we found the library. We spend roughly 30 mins in the library reading picture books. As the rain drops became very sparse, we rode to the park w/ a pond. Sea played w/ Anzu a girl she just met.  At about 6PM we left the park and I pushed the bike+trailer+kids up the mountain to come home.  S came home from work before us.  S cooked ゴーヤチャンプルー and 大葉genovese macaroni.  @2021-08-22 23:16
 FILE: IMGP0033-2021-08-22-22-45.JPG @2021-08-22 22:45
 FILE: IMGP0031-2021-08-22-22-45.JPG @2021-08-22 22:45)</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 23:22:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-08-19</title><description>(Rainy. Testing and interview for the welding course at polytech.  Test was more difficult than I imagined.  @2021-08-19 22:45
 Rainy. ハローワーク失業認定日.  @2021-08-19 22:45)</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 22:45:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-08-18</title><description>(Cloudy w/ some rain. Called S and told I have pain in my body. She advise me to go to 整体. I called and went to 神山整体. The pain in the shoulder and the eye were gone.  先生 Saizawa says my left kidney is swelling and recommended me to warm it with hot towel.  I drove to the T station to pick S and kids up.  We came home and watched 魔女の宅急便.  S and I ate one cookie each. @2021-08-18 22:22)</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 22:22:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-08-17</title><description>(FILE: IMGP0008-2021-08-18-22-25.JPG @2021-08-17 22:25
 FILE: IMGP0007-2021-08-18-22-25.JPG @2021-08-17 22:25
 8/17 Rainy.  Kuma let me stay a while before going home. We ate cookies and talked.  The left-half of my body ached a lot.  After noon I wore Kuma's rain jacket and rode the cub home.  At home I baked the pan again and watched 魔女の宅急便 and cried. @2021-08-17 22:15)</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 22:25:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-08-16</title><description>(8/16 Cloudy. I baked viet nam style croissant.  Rode the cub west and hit Kuma house.  Take came and us 3 had dinner together.  Kuma cooked 猪肉ハンバーグ with papricas. It was delicious.  感謝. @2021-08-16 22:09)</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 22:09:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-08-15</title><description>(気になる: 『中世の貧民』, 長沢オリゴ糖 @2021-08-15 22:34
 AIというのが単一のソフトウェアではなく、インターネットに宿る意識体とする。大昔から意識の入れ物ができるのを待っていたのだ。政府や企業は色々な監視テクノロジーを使うけれど、自分の意識をその上のレベルに置いて、そんなことは気にしないという世界があるんなじゃないか、と教えてもらった。 @2021-08-15 22:13
 Visited M-san after grape yesterday w/ Take. M's mother passed away a few days ago. M's brother played the crystal bowls and it was cosmic. We ate together afterward.  Met Chiyo mama, Y-kun, M-san sista. Big 感謝。 @2021-08-15 22:06)</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 22:34:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-08-14</title><description>(FILE: IMGP0006-2021-08-18-22-25.JPG @2021-08-14 22:25)</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 22:25:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-08-13</title><description>(FILE: IMGP0001-2021-08-18-22-24.JPG @2021-08-13 22:24
 Learned about the mancala board game. @2021-08-13 21:14
 書籍購入: 『エレクトロニクスをはじめよう』 Japanese edition of Getting Started in Electronics.  I myself know most of the topics covered but I bought it because it's a good book. @2021-08-13 21:14
 Re-applied for welding course at polytech because I missed the last testing and interview. @2021-08-13 21:11)</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 22:24:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-08-10</title><description>(Set up an outside work space using hemp 蚊帳. @2021-08-10 19:51
 年金免除申請。国保支払い1期と2期分。 @2021-08-10 19:47
 FILE: IMGP0043-2021-08-10-19-45.JPG @2021-08-10 19:45
 FILE: IMGP0042-2021-08-10-19-45.JPG @2021-08-10 19:45
 FILE: IMGP0040-2021-08-10-19-45.JPG @2021-08-10 19:45
 FILE: IMGP0038-2021-08-10-19-45.JPG @2021-08-10 19:45
 FILE: IMGP0034-2021-08-10-19-44.JPG @2021-08-10 19:44
 FILE: IMGP0037-2021-08-10-19-44.JPG @2021-08-10 19:44
 Sky's been fighting off cold for past couple of days. I slept w/ sky until noon. In the afternoon she went out w/ her sista and mama. @2021-08-10 19:40)</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 19:51:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-08-08</title><description>(種給水中 @2021-08-08 22:00
 My knee hasn't fully recovered from the macbook incident. @2021-08-08 21:59
 自転車のサドル位置を大胆に上げたらとても漕ぎやすくなった。今まで何をしていたんだろう。 @2021-08-08 21:58)</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2021 22:00:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-08-06</title><description>(FILE: IMGP0025-2021-08-10-19-42.JPG @2021-08-06 23:59
 大ケヤキまで走って登った時、水分を持っていなくて脱水症状になりかけたのでハイドレーションバッグを注文した。大ケヤキは麓から約4km、平均傾斜率9%。山の上は空の世界。 @2021-08-06 21:18
 今日はポリテクの選考の日だったが、すっかり忘れて仕事に出ていた。電話がかかってきて気づいて、一度辞退となったが、もう一度電話で聞いてみたら、募集が18日まで延長されていると教えてくれた。危機一髪。次は忘れないように！！ @2021-08-06 21:09
 WORK: w/ keita in yoshino-cho awa-city. @2021-08-06 21:06)</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 23:59:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-08-05</title><description>(Baked pizza in a dutch oven on wood stove. @2021-08-05 21:45
 Went to 文化の森 to see the Art Scene with Bicycles 自転車のある情景 exhibition.  The air conditioning chilled my organs and bones and I got sick afterward. exhibition was fun though. @2021-08-05 21:44)</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 21:45:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-08-04</title><description>(FILE: IMGP0008-2021-08-04-23-33.JPG @2021-08-04 23:33
 FILE: IMGP0003-2021-08-04-23-33.JPG @2021-08-04 23:33
 FILE: IMGP0001-2021-08-04-23-33.JPG @2021-08-04 23:33
 FILE: IMGP0012-2021-08-04-23-33.JPG @2021-08-04 23:33
 FILE: IMGP0010-2021-08-04-23-33.JPG @2021-08-04 23:33
 FILE: IMGP0008-2021-08-04-23-32.JPG @2021-08-04 23:32
 FILE: IMGP0004-2021-08-04-23-32.JPG @2021-08-04 23:32
 FILE: IMGP0003-2021-08-04-23-32.JPG @2021-08-04 23:32
 頂き物: ピーマンときゅうり、はちみつ、黒鯛3匹となす。 @2021-08-04 23:21
 夕方、川にシマドジョウを獲りに行った。ドジョウは2匹、モクズガニの子ども一匹、それから、なんと脂の乗った鮎を一匹掬った。 @2021-08-04 23:20
 sea and sky went to the dentist. @2021-08-04 23:17
 RUN: 大ケヤキ　朝 @2021-08-04 23:11)</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 23:33:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-08-03</title><description>(朝からピピが遊びに来た。昼、うどんを作って食べた。午後、海が河原でカイツブリの骸を発見。ピピと鳥を石で囲んで、積み上げて、長い石で屋根を作ってお墓を作った。 @2021-08-03 21:17
 FILE: IMGP0006-2021-08-03-21-13.JPG @2021-08-03 21:13
 FILE: IMGP0005-2021-08-03-21-13.JPG @2021-08-03 21:13
 FILE: IMGP0004-2021-08-03-21-13.JPG @2021-08-03 21:13
 FILE: IMGP0003-2021-08-03-21-13.JPG @2021-08-03 21:13
 FILE: IMGP0001-2021-08-03-21-12.JPG @2021-08-03 21:12
 FILE: IMGP0004-2021-08-03-21-12.JPG @2021-08-03 21:12
 FILE: IMGP0003-2021-08-03-21-12.JPG @2021-08-03 21:12
 FILE: IMGP0002-2021-08-03-21-12.JPG @2021-08-03 21:12
 明日、天を歯医者に連れて行く。たぶんサホライドという虫歯進行止めを塗るという話になるのだと思う。サホライドの成分はフッ化ジアミン銀で、フッ素と銀が入っているらしい。フッ素は松果体に蓄積して石灰化を引き起こす可能性が指摘されているが、日本では耳にすることが殆ど無い。改めて論文を読んでみた。フッ素は脳血液関門を突破しないが、松果体は脳の器官でありながら血液脳関門の外にあり、血液中のフッ素を蓄積する。個人差が大きいが、老齢の人の松果体は歯と同じ程度のフッ素を含む。松果体のフッ素濃度と骨のフッ素濃度には相関がないため、松果体のフッ素濃度は長期間に渡るフッ素への曝露を示すものではない。松果体のフッ素濃度は松果体のカルシウム濃度と強い相関がある。 @2021-08-03 19:03)</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 21:17:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-08-02</title><description>(7 o'clock in the morning. trail running w/ mio and kids. we run to the river and swam. then we each ate a cucumber, a rice ball, and a boiled egg mio prepared for breakfast. @2021-08-02 23:14)</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 23:14:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-08-01</title><description>(海は水の中で目を開けて5mくらい泳げるようになった。 @2021-08-01 22:16)</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 22:17:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-07-29</title><description>(SCHEDULE: 8/2 7:00 trail running w/ kids @2021-07-29 21:54
 Ate unagi and suika for evening meal. @2021-07-29 21:53
 Biked w/ sea on the front seat to maruike and bought juice. Then to the river and swam.  S came back from sky's dental checkup and showed up at the river. They too swam and we came home. @2021-07-29 21:53
 Backed up and compressed (resized) the photos on the phone. @2021-07-29 21:50
 Morning. Went to au shop to get my phone fixed. It hasn't been receiving SMS for a few weeks. The staff was kind and the phone got fixed. @2021-07-29 21:50
 FILE: IMGP0058-2021-07-29-21-48.JPG @2021-07-29 21:48
 FILE: IMGP0047-2021-07-29-21-47.JPG @2021-07-29 21:47
 FILE: IMGP0035-2021-07-29-21-46.JPG @2021-07-29 21:46
 FILE: IMGP0031-2021-07-29-21-46.JPG @2021-07-29 21:46
 FILE: IMGP0030-2021-07-29-21-46.JPG @2021-07-29 21:46
 FILE: IMGP0025-2021-07-29-21-45.JPG @2021-07-29 21:45
 FILE: IMGP0023-2021-07-29-21-45.JPG @2021-07-29 21:45
 FILE: IMGP0017-2021-07-29-21-45.JPG @2021-07-29 21:45)</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 22:01:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-07-28</title><description>(FILE: IMGP0010-2021-07-28-09-21.JPG @2021-07-28 09:21
 FILE: IMGP0009-2021-07-28-09-21.JPG @2021-07-28 09:21
 FILE: IMGP0001-2021-07-28-09-20.JPG @2021-07-28 09:20
 Climed up Hirono-fuji on bicycle. Slept with my whole body aching. @2021-07-28 09:19
 Played in the river with sea. Met kamata-san's daughter and kids. We crushed open an water melon and ate it. @2021-07-28 09:16
 Applied for welding course in poly-tech school starting in September. @2021-07-28 09:14)</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 09:21:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-07-27</title><description>(Switched electricity company to Tera-energy. @2021-07-27 01:15
 ポリテクセンター見学に行った。座学に不安があったが溶接科はひたすら実習が多いと聞いて安心。通ってみたいと思う。 @2021-07-27 01:13
 payed electricity and gas bill. @2021-07-27 01:12)</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 02:22:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-07-26</title><description>(RUN: up to tourou. Started at 7:45. Found a beetle on the way down. @2021-07-26 09:08)</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 09:08:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-07-25</title><description>(長野家で夕食. 鹿児島出身と四川出身のカップルがゲスト。鹿児島は水道か泉源か選べる。外の暗闇の沼のようなヌルヌルでどれだけ深いかわからない源泉に入れるところがある。四川料理は辛さに加えて花椒などのシビレが特徴。辛いだけでは美味しくない。四川の子供は揚げた野菜に唐辛子の粉を付けたものがおやつ。老干媽のラー油が美味しいそう。 @2021-07-25 23:20
 FILE: IMGP0026-2021-07-25-23-23.JPG @2021-07-25 23:23
 FILE: IMGP0025-2021-07-25-23-23.JPG @2021-07-25 23:23
 FILE: IMGP0023-2021-07-25-23-23.JPG @2021-07-25 23:23
 FILE: IMGP0012-2021-07-25-23-22.JPG @2021-07-25 23:22
 FILE: IMGP0011-2021-07-25-23-22.JPG @2021-07-25 23:22
 FILE: IMGP0010-2021-07-25-23-22.JPG @2021-07-25 23:22
 ここ2日、自転車で阿波市まで行っている。朝の吉野川の青が最高。2日目から元気になる。 @2021-07-25 23:18
 FILE: IMGP0006-2021-07-25-23-22.JPG @2021-07-25 23:22
 FILE: IMGP0005-2021-07-25-23-22.JPG @2021-07-25 23:22
 FILE: IMGP0003-2021-07-25-23-22.JPG @2021-07-25 23:22)</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 23:20:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-07-23</title><description>(bike w/ sky in the evening to the river. @2021-07-23 20:37
 kids play in the river. yasuko family, tsuru family, odapu  &amp; riku. @2021-07-23 20:37
 07/22 Rode bike w/ 波 and bought ういろう for おやつ. Then we met Tsuru with kids and Xav and family by the river. @2021-07-23 08:55)</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 20:37:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-07-22</title><description>(FILE: IMGP0016-2021-07-23-08-33.JPG @2021-07-22 08:33
 FILE: IMGP0013-2021-07-23-08-31.JPG @2021-07-22 08:31
 FILE: IMGP0012-2021-07-23-08-31.JPG @2021-07-22 08:31
 FILE: IMGP0005-2021-07-23-08-31.JPG @2021-07-22 08:31
 FILE: IMGP0004-2021-07-23-08-31.JPG @2021-07-22 08:31
 FILE: IMGP0002-2021-07-23-08-31.JPG @2021-07-22 08:31)</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 08:35:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-07-21</title><description>(RUN: toro started at quater past 6 @2021-07-21 07:48)</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 07:48:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-07-20</title><description>(make thumbnail half-size for photos with faces. @2021-07-20 22:11
 TODO: 四股の踏み方調べる @2021-07-20 20:51
 剪定屑を放れる場所を大家さんに聞いたら、裏山の広い土地を紹介してくれた。牧場ができるほど広い。鹿がたくさん来る模様。 @2021-07-20 20:48
 7/19 上分でじゃがいも堀り。かまだ庵に泊まる。 @2021-07-20 20:41
 FILE: IMGP0011-2021-07-20-20-39.JPG @2021-07-20 20:39
 FILE: IMGP0009-2021-07-20-20-39.JPG @2021-07-20 20:39
 FILE: IMGP0005-2021-07-20-20-39.JPG @2021-07-20 20:39
 FILE: IMGP0001-2021-07-20-20-38.JPG @2021-07-20 20:38
 FILE: IMGP0006-2021-07-20-20-38.JPG @2021-07-20 20:38
 FILE: IMGP0007-2021-07-20-20-38.JPG @2021-07-20 20:38)</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 22:11:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-07-19</title><description>NIL</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 10:30:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-07-18</title><description>(TIP: 雨の日の焚き火の仕方。立ち枯れた枝を割り箸くらい細く割って使う。by大福 @2021-07-18 23:37
 FILE: IMGP0005-2021-07-18-23-12.JPG @2021-07-18 23:12
 Rode cub to Takeshi's and conspired to save the house from demolishing. @2021-07-18 22:48
 Us 4 + 2 went by bus to Awagin hall to watch 阿波人形浄瑠璃.  三番叟,義太夫メドレー,伊達娘恋緋鹿子 火の見櫓の段,壺坂観音霊験記　沢市内の段,コンテンポ太夫.　Then e ate lunch outside then we took a boat ride. @2021-07-18 22:47
 07/17 We bathed in the onsen near the camping field and drove home. Manami w/ Akari came and we ate spaghetti for dinner togather. They stayed at our place for the night. @2021-07-18 22:38
 07/17 A family of 6 arrived in the morning to the camp site and set up their camp.  Sea made friends with the kids and soon we were playing together.  They work in hospitals and the father told us about the reality hospitals are facing against covid.  His blog: https://hirokz530.hatenablog.com/ @2021-07-18 22:36
 FILE: IMGP0019-2021-07-18-22-29.JPG @2021-07-18 22:29
 FILE: IMGP0018-2021-07-18-22-29.JPG @2021-07-18 22:29
 FILE: IMGP0016-2021-07-18-22-29.JPG @2021-07-18 22:29
 FILE: IMGP0014-2021-07-18-22-29.JPG @2021-07-18 22:29
 FILE: IMGP0012-2021-07-18-22-29.JPG @2021-07-18 22:29
 FILE: IMGP0010-2021-07-18-22-29.JPG @2021-07-18 22:29
 FILE: IMGP0009-2021-07-18-22-29.JPG @2021-07-18 22:29
 FILE: IMGP0008-2021-07-18-22-29.JPG @2021-07-18 22:29
 FILE: IMGP0004-2021-07-18-22-29.JPG @2021-07-18 22:29
 07/16 To Awaji-shima. S went to take pranayama class. Sea, sky, and I played in the beach.  Sea caught a baby lizard. Camped in くわがたの森 諭鶴羽ダムキャンプ場 at night. Slept listening to the sounds of ウシガエル,鈴虫,フクロウ. @2021-07-18 22:27
 FILE: IMGP0008-2021-07-20-20-35.JPG @2021-07-18 20:35
 FILE: IMGP0007-2021-07-20-20-35.JPG @2021-07-18 20:35
 FILE: IMGP0006-2021-07-20-20-35.JPG @2021-07-18 20:35
 FILE: IMGP0005-2021-07-20-20-35.JPG @2021-07-18 20:35)</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 23:37:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-07-15</title><description>(娘達と散歩をしていたら川上さんとこの犬のラブが逃げ出してついて来た。川上さん家まで一緒に歩いて帰ったら、野菜をたくさんくれた。とうもろこし、ナス、白ナス、きゅうり、トマト。ありがとう。 @2021-07-15 05:36
 07/14　河原で寝た。朝、昨日のお遍路さんに会いに行った。マムシの皮を剥いて干しておく。傷跡に貼ると治る。マムシに噛まれた時は、血清は打たず、皮を貼る。ただし病院には行くこと。血清は2回までしか効かない。人はだれもが一つ超能力を持っている。二つ持っている人はめったにいない。出るか出ないかはその人次第。現代の地球の精神年齢は中学生。だから戦争も起きる。とのこと。 @2021-07-15 05:32)</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 23:54:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-07-13</title><description>(夕方散歩していたら、休憩所で、歩き遍路のおじさんに出会った。理想の世界はありえない。なんでもかんでも叶うわけじゃない。ということをわかった上で、拝み続けている。無縁仏やお地蔵さんを掃除したり手入れしたり。家はなく、托鉢で、23年間回り続けているそう。とある寺で、「修行がしたい」と口走ったらこの通り。地球というところはありえないことがたくさんあって、どこまで本気にしたらいいかわからない。宇宙人の実験場なのではないか。アメリカとロシアは知っているがなかなか表には出てこない。古代に進んだ文明があったことは間違いない。現代の人間は言語のタガを嵌められている。バグダッドの電池とか、巨石文明とか、ナスカの地上絵とか、ガラス化した都市とか。サイババと石槌山の天狗はイギリスの金融街にいる。兄ちゃんは、自分の位置を見極めて、そこで頑張ったほうが良い。この稼業はよしたほうが良いよ。花粉症の治し方:冬イチゴの葉を乾燥させてお茶にして毎日飲む。　冷え性:それに効くヨガのポーズがあるはずだからそれ一つだけやってごらん。など。　話したら元気が出た。 @2021-07-13 22:19
 海と、水の中の微生物を虫眼鏡と顕微鏡で観察した。 @2021-07-13 13:30
 SCHEDULE: 7/26 ポリテク溶接科見学 @2021-07-13 11:39
 SCHEDULE: 7/20, 21 PLANTS @2021-07-13 11:38)</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 22:20:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-07-12</title><description>(COOKED: カボチャのシュレッドケーキのパイ @2021-07-12 20:02
 書店で『エネルギーの愉快な発明史』という本と、簡易顕微鏡セットを買って、バスで帰った。 @2021-07-12 20:02
 明け方、ラジオでマラソン選手の母親のインタビューを聞いて、山の上まで走った。帰宅後味噌汁をつくって食べて、海、天を送る。その後庭のジャングル化した一角を開拓。午後はハローワークへ行って、スタンプをもらって職業訓練の相談。 @2021-07-12 19:52
 RUN: 5AM 19min uphill to Toro. @2021-07-12 06:22
 Mixed cooked kome with kome-koji and set it in the yogurt maker hoping it turns into ama-zake. @2021-07-12 02:13
 Watching video to make raw vegan onion bread @2021-07-12 02:09
 Replied to Charlotte @2021-07-12 02:08)</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 20:02:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-07-11</title><description>(After dinner I walked in the dark to the resting place and thought about the circuitry and plan to travel on bike for funding. @2021-07-11 11:59
 We parked the car in front of liquor store/bike shop/outdoor clothing shop/botanical shop and walked to and played in the park nearby.  Walked back and before we drove off I checked out the specs of electric assist bikes on display at the bike shop. It's capable of powering at eco mode for 21km at the cost of big battery and big hub motor. @2021-07-11 11:59
 Watched Asaterasu 2 about the man w/cancer who fought for his right to pursue happiness and to live in court when he was arrested for posession of cannabis.  Met Kantoku, Mariko, Hisa, and Akarihan. @2021-07-11 11:59
 07/10 Bought yogurt maker and water tank at Taiyo+Midori. S went to Hiwasa w/ kids. @2021-07-11 11:59
 FILE: IMGP0132-2021-07-12-00-24.JPG @2021-07-11 11:58)</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 11:59:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-07-09</title><description>(FILE: IMGP0130-2021-07-09-22-23.JPG @2021-07-09 22:23
 FILE: IMGP0128-2021-07-09-22-23.JPG @2021-07-09 22:23
 FILE: IMGP0127-2021-07-09-22-23.JPG @2021-07-09 22:23
 FILE: IMGP0121-2021-07-09-22-22.JPG @2021-07-09 22:22
 20:20　智、最寄り駅に到着。娘達うれしそう。 @2021-07-09 21:57
 散歩中、金魚のタクシーで頂いた桃はシャキシャキで素朴な甘さで美味しかった。天は桃をかじりながら、水筒やテレビに「てぇび、おいしいねえ」とか話しかけている。テレビはついていない。 @2021-07-09 12:13
 海保育所へ、天は微熱で休み。 @2021-07-09 11:47
 07/08 天、海、保育所へ。智大阪のおばさんの御見舞へ。海帰宅1230。「ぬ」から始まる言葉、「さ」から始まる言葉などを言い合いながら、昇圧充電回路の実験。天帰宅1530。川遊び後よるご飯。魚、サンマの蒲焼き、白ご飯、ナスのピカタ。歯磨き、風呂、就寝海8時半頃、天はテレビを見てから10時頃寝た。ブドウ糖が不足すると肝臓で作られるケトン体を誘導する食事法で癌にならないし治るらしい。ある程度の年齢になったら糖質はいらないということだろう。天は夜中一度数分起きただけで、朝までよく寝た。 @2021-07-09 11:46
 07/07 大福が心配して電話をくれた。たけちゃんとも話した。@2021-07-09 12:35
 07/07 天、海、保育所へ。七夕集会。智二日酔い。 @2021-07-09 11:20
 OPAQUE: 07/06 夜、智狂う。スパークリングワインを一瓶開けて、「死ぬ」とか「死にそう」とか言って泣いている。40万円のヨガティーチャートレーニングを受けるとか受けないとか。このところ毎晩のように泣いている気がする。 @2021-07-09 11:15)</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 22:23:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-07-06</title><description>NIL</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 18:28:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-07-05</title><description>(FILE: IMGP0118-2021-07-05-20-51.JPG @2021-07-05 20:51
 海が「魚がいっぱい釣れておめでとうペンダント」を作ってくれた。海は誕生日に「ライフジャケットだけで泳げるようになっておめでとう」と書いて欲しいそう。 @2021-07-05 20:50
 明日は剪定 @2021-07-05 20:44
 夕方、海と天と川へ。その後じゃこ釣り。11匹釣れた。昨日衣を作りすぎたので、今日も揚げて頂いた。 @2021-07-05 20:44
 智と自転車で◯扇に行った。二人で自転車で出かけるのは本当に久しぶり。 @2021-07-05 20:42
 アレルギー対策というのは、腸内で乳酸菌を繁殖させて腸内環境を改善すると良いというあれで、フラクトオリゴ糖は乳酸菌の餌になって、糖として吸収されないとshave off mindというブログで読んだから。 @2021-07-05 20:40
 大福に教えてもらった、玄米の研ぎ汁に砂糖を入れて封をして置いておく乳酸菌を便利に使っている。洗濯、掃除、それから豆乳に入れて置いておくとヨーグルトができる。食べると口の中がビリビリするがうまい。アレルギー対策のため、フラクトオリゴ糖をかけて食べている。 @2021-07-05 20:38)</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 20:51:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-07-04</title><description>(FILE: IMGP0116-2021-07-04-22-10.JPG @2021-07-04 22:10
 FILE: IMGP0115-2021-07-04-22-10.JPG @2021-07-04 22:10
 FILE: IMGP0113-2021-07-04-22-09.JPG @2021-07-04 22:09
 FILE: IMGP0112-2021-07-04-22-09.JPG @2021-07-04 22:09
 FILE: IMGP0110-2021-07-04-22-09.JPG @2021-07-04 22:09
 FILE: IMGP0109-2021-07-04-22-09.JPG @2021-07-04 22:09
 FILE: IMGP0107-2021-07-04-22-09.JPG @2021-07-04 22:09)</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 22:10:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-07-03</title><description>(juel caterpiller @2021-07-03 21:16
 FILE: IMGP0105-2021-07-03-21-16.JPG @2021-07-03 21:16
 MUSIC: 岡村孝子 @2021-07-03 21:15
 実験記録: 自転車の車輪に取り付けた磁石の回転を600回巻Φ30mmの空芯コイルで拾うと、開放電圧約1.5V 周波数高々10Hz程度。コイルを増やすか昇圧する必要がある。コイルを増やすのは位相を合わせるのが難しい。昇圧の場合低周波ではトランスが重く大きくなるので、倍圧整流後にマルチバイブレータで高周波発振してトロイドコアに手巻きしたトランスで4倍に昇圧して、倍圧でキャパシタを充電するようにした。発電が止まると電荷が抜けていくのが、どこから漏れているのか突き止める必要有り。 @2021-07-03 21:14
 カメラを持ち歩く癖が抜けてしまって、色々撮り損ねている。 @2021-07-03 20:58
 天と夜の散歩。ゲジゲジを見つけて喜んでいた。 @2021-07-03 20:58
 炒り玄米粥は薪で炊かないとおいしくならない。子どもたちも食べない。 @2021-07-03 20:57)</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 21:16:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-07-01</title><description>(消防点検 @2021-07-01 22:18
 公園でお手玉を縫った。中身は小豆。良い小豆を使ってしまったのでいつか食べないと。 @2021-07-01 22:14
 FILE: IMGP0104-2021-07-01-22-13.JPG @2021-07-01 22:13
 昨夜、天の咳がひどくなり、慌てて自然療法の本を見る。梅干しを気管支と背中に貼ると良いというので、ガーゼで袋を縫って、手拭いを立てに裂いたものに縫い付けて、袋に梅干しを入れて巻いて縛った。朝、冷やしていた大根はちみつ液を猪口に入れて渡すと、微妙な顔をしながら全部飲んだ。昼からは元気になり海と一緒に公園に行って、池の鯉と亀を見た。朝薪で炊いておいた炒り玄米小豆粥が美味しくて、皆よく食べた。炒り玄米粥はじめて作った。一合のお米が4号くらいに増えて、満足感もある。 @2021-07-01 22:11)</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 22:18:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-06-30</title><description>(prepare web interface for posting @2021-06-30 21:58)</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 21:58:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-06-29</title><description>(土を掘って金盥を埋めて石で囲んで亀の池を作った。金盥で行けるのか要調査 @2021-06-29 21:29)</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 21:29:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-06-28</title><description>(planted seeds @2021-06-28 22:43 PROJECT: 竹製農具小屋兼立体菜園 @2021-06-28 22:42
 TODO: call takeshi about charlotte's request @2021-06-28 22:41
 LINK: 10円玉の重さで発電 https://gijyutu.com/main/archives/646 @2021-06-28 22:41
 600 turn 0.2mm aprox 3cm diameter 5mm thickness achieved 900mA AC @2021-06-28 22:38
 色々したようであまり何もしていないような一日であった。起床後2階へ、海を送った後、河原で朝寝。活元運動ののち、泳いでから帰宅。亀にミミズをやったり、洗濯物を干したり、薪ストーブで調理して家の湿気を飛ばしたり。海は昼過ぎに帰宅。夕方自転車の実験。夜、珍しくホットプレートで焼肉。食器を洗った後、天の咳がひどいので大根はちみつ液を作ったが、飲まなくて、無理に飲ませてしまい吐いた。ついむきになってしまうことがあり、なるべく立ち入らずそっとしておきたいとよく思っている。服をたたんで居間を片付けて、日記を書いて寝る。 @2021-06-28 22:36
 found a baby green turtle in the pond in the park and sea came home with it. @2021-06-28 01:14)</description><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 22:43:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-06-25</title><description>(ジャグリング再開したい。お手玉が良いかも。 @2021-06-25 20:20
 鷺の営巣地を見に、家族でバスで出かけた。鷺の巣には100羽くらいの白鷺がいて、周囲にはアオサギやシギ？などの水鳥がいた。圧巻。その後カニを拾ったりして帰ってきた。 @2021-06-25 20:18)</description><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 20:20:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-06-24</title><description>(FILE: IMGP0084-2021-06-24-20-56.JPG @2021-06-24 20:56
 FILE: IMGP0078-2021-06-24-20-56.JPG @2021-06-24 20:56
 ワイシャツの衿を和服風に仕立て直す方法を編み出した。 @2021-06-24 20:55
 Walked w/ sea and sky to shop 甘酒. Stopped by taxi station and watched 金魚. お母さん gave us 豆じゃが.  参詣 祠. Picked many 沢蟹.  Fried them and ate for dinner. Biked back to 祠 and お供え beer mini can. @2021-06-24 20:51
 Then I went to 100 yen shop to buy sea's swimming bag, then to 徳島城, then udon, then biked home in the rain and got soaking wet. @2021-06-24 20:47
 SCHEDULE: 8/19 hellowork @2021-06-24 20:46
 Biked to hellowork. I have to go one more time before next 認定日 which is 8/19. @2021-06-24 20:45
 Morning, baked bread in the dutch oven on fire outside, cooked cha-han w/ left over rice, egg, lettuce, and negi. Then cooked rice. @2021-06-24 20:42
 Slept on the sand by the river. Ground sheet, sleeping bag, artificial wool blanket, and bamboo pillow.  Heared strange sound before dawn like fighter jet passing by at very high altitude. @2021-06-24 20:42)</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 21:01:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-06-23</title><description>(FILE: IMGP0086-2021-06-24-20-57.JPG @2021-06-23 20:57
 モノストックで頂いた浴衣がとても肌触りが良い。 @2021-06-23 21:28
 よく食べてしまう。体重は増えないが、食べれば食べるだけ体調が悪くなる。 @2021-06-23 21:27
 神山整体で教えてもらったことで書き忘れていたこと。梅雨の時期は腎臓に負担がかかる。生き物として、なるべく動かずにじっとしている時期。腎臓を温めると良い。腰の上、背中側に手を当てる。体を捻ることも刺激になる。少食が良い。 @2021-06-23 21:27
 SCHEDULE: 6/26 Sat adopt @2021-06-23 19:17
 ある特定の植物のことを離れたところで考えると、その植物の電位に変化が生じるという話を前につよしさんから聞いたことを思い出した。 @2021-06-23 19:15
 大福　「鳴門から池田まで踊り続ける阿波踊りをやりたい。よってきた人が入っていって1000人位に膨れ上がりたい。」 @2021-06-23 19:12)</description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 20:57:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-06-22</title><description>(TODO: write a blog post about vaccine. Untested mRNA vaccine is dangerous. @2021-06-22 21:00
 tsutsuji sentei at kamata-san's @2021-06-22 20:58
 shikibi sentei at wakakusa. @2021-06-22 20:58
 6/21 Weeding w/ hikaru. @2021-06-22 06:43)</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 21:00:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-06-20</title><description>(Changed bicycle chain. Connecting pin broke before push and I ended up reusing the pin from the chain. Took 2 hours. @2021-06-20 21:34
 Last night sea and I slept outside. @2021-06-20 21:33
 FILE: IMGP0076-2021-06-20-21-31.JPG @2021-06-20 21:31
 FILE: IMGP0074-2021-06-20-21-31.JPG @2021-06-20 21:31
 FILE: IMGP0073-2021-06-20-21-31.JPG @2021-06-20 21:31
 FILE: IMGP0072-2021-06-20-21-31.JPG @2021-06-20 21:31)</description><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 21:34:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-06-18</title><description>(神山整体へ。体癖は9番と6番ではないか。体重が前にかかっている。など。楽になった。 @2021-06-18 21:32
 made outside kitchen out of bamboo, cheap sugi beams, and some rope. @2021-06-18 21:32
 FILE: IMGP0071-2021-06-20-21-31.JPG @2021-06-18 21:31
 FILE: IMGP0068-2021-06-20-21-30.JPG @2021-06-18 21:30)</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 21:32:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-06-15</title><description>(DEV: integrate biwascheme to shortblog @2021-06-15 22:27
 TODO: deposit some money to the bank. @2021-06-15 21:52
 普段の生活をしていてしょっちゅう出てくる不調なら、自分で治す方法を見つけるしかないと思って色々な方法を試してきたが、どこがどうずれているのかという観察が足りなかった。 @2021-06-15 19:46
 肩の痛みについて調べた。左だけ肩甲骨が出っ張っている。肩も左だけ前に出ている。巻き肩というらしい。ここに載っている対策を試したら、肩が戻って痛みも改善した。　https://mitsuraku.jp/kiji/rolled-shoulder-stretch @2021-06-15 19:42
 05/14　大福ファミリー帰る。熱が出た。前日から左の鼻と喉と肩が痛かった。 @2021-06-15 19:37
 05/13　あわひ　上映会。カントク、陽子さん、つるちゃん、おさかだ一家、大福一家。 @2021-06-15 19:36
 FILE: IMGP0067-2021-06-15-19-32.JPG @2021-06-15 19:32
 FILE: IMGP0066-2021-06-15-19-32.JPG @2021-06-15 19:32
 FILE: IMGP0061-2021-06-15-19-32.JPG @2021-06-15 19:32
 FILE: IMGP0055-2021-06-15-19-32.JPG @2021-06-15 19:32)</description><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 22:27:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-06-13</title><description>(Spoke generator スポーク発電　トランスと磁石とスポークで発電できるらしい https://youtu.be/Af9r_J3n4qg @2021-06-13 00:55
 Reserched about eddy current.  @2021-06-13 00:54
 In the evening, I went to maruike w/ sky and sea. Sea on her bike. @2021-06-13 00:54
 Picked more biwa and sent it to megu. @2021-06-13 00:54
 Bought bike chain at local bike shop for 2500 yen.  When I got back home I checked the price on the net and it was 1200!  Ripoff! @2021-06-13 00:53
 Biked to Jorakuji. Sat then slept. @2021-06-13 00:50
 Kta gave us potatos a few days ago. In return I brought them biwa in the morning. @2021-06-13 00:49
 Electromagnet -&gt; EDLC -&gt; electromagnet altenate drive @2021-06-13 00:48
 FILE: IMGP0053-2021-06-13-00-47.JPG @2021-06-13 00:47
 FILE: IMGP0052-2021-06-13-00-47.JPG @2021-06-13 00:47
 FILE: IMGP0051-2021-06-13-00-47.JPG @2021-06-13 00:47
 FILE: IMGP0050-2021-06-13-00-47.JPG @2021-06-13 00:47
 FILE: IMGP0046-2021-06-13-00-46.JPG @2021-06-13 00:46
 FILE: IMGP0045-2021-06-13-00-46.JPG @2021-06-13 00:46
 FILE: IMGP0043-2021-06-13-00-46.JPG @2021-06-13 00:46)</description><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 00:55:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-06-10</title><description>(HIGHLIGHT: 「早起き-&gt;家事-&gt;自転車-&gt;仮眠---&gt;活動」 I think I found the way to function. @2021-06-10 21:13
 watched たそがれ清兵衛 @2021-06-10 21:10 Picked biwa w/ Ayumi @2021-06-10 21:09
 Woke up at 6. Cleaned and cooked. Left house before others woke up. Biked to the park and ate 炒飯 I brought, slept for an hour or so. Then I worked out the circuitry for experimental ac power source while doing ゆる体操. Went home after grocery. @2021-06-10 21:08)</description><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 21:13:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-06-09</title><description>(Worked out the schematics for Wheel motor EDLC electric assist bike. @2021-06-09 19:06
 FILE: IMGP0040-2021-06-09-19-04.JPG @2021-06-09 19:04
 FILE: IMGP0036-2021-06-09-19-04.JPG @2021-06-09 19:04
 FILE: IMGP0030-2021-06-09-19-03.JPG @2021-06-09 19:03
 FILE: IMGP0028-2021-06-09-19-03.JPG @2021-06-09 19:03
 蛇をよく見る。アオダイショウ、マムシ、黒い蛇 @2021-06-09 02:02
 Went to dinner with Hikaru and Odapu at Osho, then to Coco's for coffee. We talked until the restaurant close at 1am. @2021-06-09 01:34
 Picked biwa and distributed among neighbours. @2021-06-09 01:30
 Came home. Went to the river with fam and swam. I ate somen afterward.  @2021-06-09 01:29
 Grandma has entered the care-home. @2021-06-09 01:29
 Called hikaru to discuss the request from thinkup.  Called father to ask for detail. @2021-06-09 01:28
 It was painful to wake up. I biked to 常楽寺 in the morning and climbed the hill behind it.  Found a nice bench with a roof and took a nap.  Woke up refreshed @2021-06-09 01:26)</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 19:06:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-06-07</title><description>(くまちゃんに教えてもらったゆる体操を実践中。あとは井本整体の人体力学ストレッチと、喉仏を押すことをしている。 @2021-06-07 22:48
 今朝は海、天を保育園に送っていって、天が帰ってくるまでの間に100均にネオジム磁石を買いに行った。海が帰ってきてから川に言ってドンコの子をたくさん獲って食べた。智に梅醤番茶を作ってもらった。 @2021-06-07 22:44
 良いこと:　ヨモギ風呂。頭を洗う。背中をこする。 @2021-06-07 22:41
 枇杷が豊作。たくさん食べた。家族に送ろうか。 @2021-06-07 22:39 コバエが異常に多い @2021-06-07 22:38)</description><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 22:48:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-06-05</title><description>(目標: 早起き @2021-06-05 10:44)</description><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 10:44:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-06-04</title><description>(青空文庫の童話を読み聞かせるポッドキャストを見つけて気に入った。 @2021-06-04 20:50
 海の内股矯正用インソールとボトムブラケット+スプロケットレンチのセットを注文した。 amazonで買い物は控えたいが、たまにしかたなく使ってしまう。 @2021-06-04 20:39
 S evacuates the house.  I stayed home with sea and sky.  We wore rain poncho and went walking.  We found 枇杷、沢蟹、蝸牛、筍、梅、桑の実(malberry).  For lunch I cooked 炒飯 w/ 筍 and 沢蟹 I picked up.  Tip: to make 炒飯 パラパラ be sure to wash the cold rice w/ water. @2021-06-04 20:37
 Woke up with my body feeling best in past couple months. No pain in back/neck/shoulder/tail.  @2021-06-04 20:32)</description><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 20:50:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-06-03</title><description>(After much searching and reading, I decided what I need to do are experiments, not reading @2021-06-03 23:56
 I made up my mind and ordered 12 100F3V EDLCs. @2021-06-03 23:37
 コンビニで雨に振り込められて困っていたらKta君が家族で通りがかり、乗せてくれた。 @2021-06-03 22:43
 説明会受講中どうしようもなく体が凝って気持ちが悪くなった。帰りのバスでも座ったらすぐに体がこわばり気持ちが悪くなったので、ストレッチをしたり首を回したりしている内に、喉仏の左側を強く押し込むと、左の鼻が通って、肩にも刺激があることを発見した。頚椎2番がおかしいと複数の所見を得ているので、それに関係しているかも。しばらく試してみようと思う。 @2021-06-03 22:43
 デパート6階の書店で、電車の絵本と電気の伝記と、隣の店でサングラスを見た。見ただけで買わなかったけど、家に帰ってきてからやっぱり欲しいと思った。 @2021-06-03 22:39
 ハローワークで失業給付受給説明会。月2回の就職活動と、失業状態の申告に行く必要があるそう。できるかな。ポリテクに通う、または再就職手当の受給も検討中。溶接を学ぶのには興味がある。 @2021-06-03 22:37
 went to konan pro and bought some wood beams, paint cans, bamboo saw, screws, and canvas tool bag. @2021-06-03 22:34)</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 23:56:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-06-02</title><description>(明日3時からハローワークで失業給付受給者説明会 @2021-06-02 22:23
 PROJECT: EDLC coil assist bike @2021-06-02 22:16
 PROJECT: portable carrier-powered crystal radio @2021-06-02 22:15
 レイズドベッドのキッチンガーデンに土を入れて、苗を植えた。嵩増しのために底には刈草を入れ、その上に川砂、消し炭、灰、それから刈草積み場の底の土を混ぜて乗せた。土が浅すぎるかも。植えたものはレタス、唐辛子、ナス、パセリ、モロヘイヤ。コーヒーかすや米の研ぎ汁なんかを与えて育てる予定。  @2021-06-02 22:10)</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 22:23:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-06-01</title><description>(川で手長エビが一匹取れたので素揚げして皆で食べた。美味しい。少しでも、獲れたてを自分で命をいただくと、食べた後生命力がみなぎる感じがする。 @2021-06-01 22:06
 消防点検。若手ばかり6人集まって、全員で消防車に乗った。 @2021-06-01 22:05)</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 22:06:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-05-31</title><description>(anxiety kicking in a little... @2021-05-31 22:58
 Cooked ご飯 and 味噌汁 outside on the hi-tech 七輪. We ate outside @2021-05-31 22:52
 Found an earthworm and tried to fish the catfish with it. It ate the earthworm but got away by cutting the line. @2021-05-31 22:50
 昼前、健康福祉課よりメールが届く。検討した結果、熱中症対策としてマスク着用を義務づけないこととします。とのこと。保育所から保護者へ手紙で通知された模様。ひとまず良かった。 @2021-05-31 22:49
 神山町の健康福祉課に保育所での子どものマスク着用義務がWHOと厚労省の方針に反していると指摘し、現在議論中。激渋な対応で、厚労省にエスカレートするなり、保護者に文書の回覧をお願いするなりする必要があるかも。WHOは5歳以下の子供へマスク着用を要求することを薦めていない。厚労省は若干曖昧だが、子どもへの一律のマスク着用は求めないと明記している。　https://www.mhlw.go.jp/content/11920000/000672483.pdf @2021-05-31 11:45
 おととい Spoke to Benoit. He wants me to come over to Baitz+Vienna and do up the electronics for his next project. @2021-05-31 11:41
 ふきがみょうがの生息域を侵食しているのを発見し、大慌てで刈り取った。みょうがが生き延びてくれることを願う。ふきの葉は乾燥させてティッシュに、茎はきゃらぶきにした。 @2021-05-31 11:39)</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 22:58:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-05-29</title><description>(5/26 made a high-tech double-burning shichirin. @2021-05-29 05:36
 Yesterday I went to hellowork to receive unemployment insurance. I'm not supossed to work this week. @2021-05-29 05:35
 I'm battling with the local government on their policy to require kids aged 2yrs and up to wear masks in kindergarden. @2021-05-29 05:34
 S, sea, and sky came home yesterday. @2021-05-29 05:32)</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2021 05:36:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-05-26</title><description>(電気、水道、ガス代金、KMSのレンサバ代金を支払った。 @2021-05-26 22:56
 毎朝毎夕、猫と川へ行くようにしたい。 @2021-05-26 21:07
 夕方、猫と川へ行った。砂をほって糞をして、上手に埋めていた。その後畑の草踏み/取り。 @2021-05-26 21:07)</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 22:56:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-05-25</title><description>(Met 大原さん from 横浜 in Little Asia.  He climbs mountains. Gave us lots of food to eat in the mountains.  Told me about 水平歩道 in 黒部. @2021-05-25 21:30
 Went to kagoshima w/ fam. Stayed 1 night at Little Asia, 4 days at Dynamic Lab, 1 night at Little Asia, and 1 night at grandma's house.  A lot happened.  Grandma seemed to me a little happier than the last time.  I'm happy about that. @2021-05-25 21:21
 FILE: IMGP0020-2021-05-26-21-18.JPG @2021-05-25 21:18
 FILE: IMGP0019-2021-05-26-21-17.JPG @2021-05-25 21:17
 FILE: IMGP0018-2021-05-26-21-17.JPG @2021-05-25 21:17
 FILE: IMGP0011-2021-05-26-21-17.JPG @2021-05-25 21:17
 FILE: IMGP0010-2021-05-26-21-17.JPG @2021-05-25 21:17)</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 21:30:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-05-14</title><description>(おもちゃと旅する親子が来てくれた。 @2021-05-14 21:36
 FILE: IMGP0101-2021-05-26-21-36.JPG @2021-05-14 21:36
 FILE: IMGP0098-2021-05-26-21-36.JPG @2021-05-14 21:36
 FILE: IMGP0097-2021-05-26-21-36.JPG @2021-05-14 21:36
 FILE: IMGP0088-2021-05-26-21-35.JPG @2021-05-14 21:35
 FILE: IMGP0087-2021-05-26-21-35.JPG @2021-05-14 21:35
 FILE: IMGP0086-2021-05-26-21-35.JPG @2021-05-14 21:35
 FILE: IMGP0082-2021-05-26-21-35.JPG @2021-05-14 21:35
 FILE: IMGP0081-2021-05-26-21-35.JPG @2021-05-14 21:35)</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 21:36:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-05-12</title><description>(FILE: IMGP0075-2021-05-26-21-34.JPG @2021-05-12 21:34
 雨。バスで役場へ行って、国保、国民年金への切り替えを手続きした。離職票が届き次第年金支払い免除手続きすること。 @2021-05-12 22:16
 雨。役場へ年金と保険の切り替え手続きに行く予定。10:58のバスを待っている。 @2021-05-12 10:44
 5/11 強飯を炊いた。炊いたと言うか蒸した。茶碗一杯食べるのに苦労するし、お腹が一杯になる。 @2021-05-12 10:43
 5/11 went to the zoo w/ fam but it was closed so we went to the botanical garden next door. @2021-05-12 10:42
 5/11 オフィスの鍵、保険証、名刺、LiDAR、Mouse製パソコン、wimaxを返却。コンビニから送った。 @2021-05-12 10:41)</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 21:34:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-05-10</title><description>(FILE: IMGP0068-2021-05-10-21-56.JPG @2021-05-10 21:56
 FILE: IMGP0067-2021-05-10-21-56.JPG @2021-05-10 21:56)</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 21:56:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-05-08</title><description>(FILE: IMGP0055-2021-05-08-21-02.JPG @2021-05-08 21:02
 FILE: IMGP0054-2021-05-08-21-02.JPG @2021-05-08 21:02
 FILE: IMGP0052-2021-05-08-21-02.JPG @2021-05-08 21:02
 FILE: IMGP0051-2021-05-08-21-02.JPG @2021-05-08 21:02
 FILE: IMGP0049-2021-05-08-21-02.JPG @2021-05-08 21:02
 FILE: IMGP0047-2021-05-08-21-02.JPG @2021-05-08 21:02
 FILE: IMGP0045-2021-05-08-21-02.JPG @2021-05-08 21:02
 クライミングワールドカップの男子決勝戦を見た。ボルダリングの映像を見るのは初めて。とてもハラハラするし、登りきった時嬉しい。素直に感情が乗るスポーツに初めて出会った感じ。選手のコメントもぐっとくる。 @2021-05-08 20:58
 3時の休憩時にリプトンを飲んだらシュガーハイでピュンピュンした @2021-05-08 20:56
 親方から、見積もり作成の時、施工イメージの平面図と立面図をどう描けば仕事が取れるか前から相談を受けていた。パソコンで作っていないとそれだけではねられることがあるとのこと。ベクタードローイングは以前試したが難しかったよう。今日はkimisに着想を得て、絵は手描き、字はパソコンにしようということで決着。立面図は写真をなぞって描いていたけど、普通の紙を使って苦労していたようで、トレーシングペーパーというのがあると教えた。 @2021-05-08 20:55
 WORK: uemasa mima sentei @2021-05-08 20:49)</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 21:02:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-05-06</title><description>(collected matsu shoots and tiny baby pinecone. @2021-05-06 21:23
 WORK: uemasa morning/yamakawa concrete. afternoon/mima sentei w/ daifuku, fuke, kuma @2021-05-06 21:22)</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 21:23:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-05-05</title><description>(FILE: IMGP0041-2021-05-05-20-50.JPG @2021-05-05 20:50
 FILE: IMGP0038-2021-05-05-20-50.JPG @2021-05-05 20:50
 FILE: IMGP0029-2021-05-05-20-50.JPG @2021-05-05 20:50
 FILE: IMGP0028-2021-05-05-20-50.JPG @2021-05-05 20:50
 FILE: IMGP0027-2021-05-05-20-49.JPG @2021-05-05 20:49
 FILE: IMGP0023-2021-05-05-20-49.JPG @2021-05-05 20:49
 昨日大福さんと集めた松ぼっくりの赤ちゃんを煮詰めてジャムにしようとして盛大に焦げ付かせ失敗。火のそばを離れてはいけない。 @2021-05-05 10:23)</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 20:50:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-05-04</title><description>(5/4 WORK: uemasa sentei ishii aibata @2021-05-04 19:50
 5/2 keita tempura @2021-05-04 19:49
 5/1 Takoyaki party w/ masato,nanoha,kta,miki,mayui @2021-05-04 19:49
 4/30 shiitake komatsuke w/ keita + masato @2021-05-04 19:47)</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 19:50:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-04-28</title><description>(FILE: IMGP0022-2021-05-05-20-49.JPG @2021-04-28 20:49
 FILE: IMGP0021-2021-05-05-20-49.JPG @2021-04-28 20:49
 FILE: IMGP0011-2021-05-05-20-49.JPG @2021-04-28 20:49
 FILE: IMGP0008-2021-05-05-20-49.JPG @2021-04-28 20:49
 FILE: IMGP0002-2021-05-05-20-49.JPG @2021-04-28 20:49
 FILE: IMGP0001-2021-05-05-20-49.JPG @2021-04-28 20:49
 FILE: IMGP0082-2021-05-05-20-49.JPG @2021-04-28 20:49
 FILE: IMGP0081-2021-05-05-20-49.JPG @2021-04-28 20:49
 FILE: IMGP0077-2021-05-05-20-48.JPG @2021-04-28 20:48
 FILE: IMGP0076-2021-05-05-20-48.JPG @2021-04-28 20:48
 FILE: IMGP0074-2021-05-05-20-48.JPG @2021-04-28 20:48
 FILE: IMGP0072-2021-05-05-20-48.JPG @2021-04-28 20:48
 FILE: IMGP0071-2021-05-05-20-48.JPG @2021-04-28 20:48
 FILE: IMGP0068-2021-05-05-20-48.JPG @2021-04-28 20:48
 FILE: IMGP0065-2021-05-05-20-48.JPG @2021-04-28 20:48
 FILE: IMGP0061-2021-05-05-20-47.JPG @2021-04-28 20:47
 FILE: IMGP0056-2021-05-05-20-47.JPG @2021-04-28 20:47
 FILE: IMGP0052-2021-05-05-20-47.JPG @2021-04-28 20:47
 FILE: IMGP0051-2021-05-05-20-47.JPG @2021-04-28 20:47
 FILE: IMGP0048-2021-05-05-20-46.JPG @2021-04-28 20:46
 FILE: IMGP0046-2021-05-05-20-46.JPG @2021-04-28 20:46
 FILE: IMGP0044-2021-05-05-20-46.JPG @2021-04-28 20:46
 FILE: IMGP0043-2021-05-05-20-46.JPG @2021-04-28 20:46
 FILE: IMGP0041-2021-05-05-20-46.JPG @2021-04-28 20:46
 FILE: IMGP0030-2021-05-05-20-46.JPG @2021-04-28 20:46
 FILE: IMGP0029-2021-05-05-20-45.JPG @2021-04-28 20:45
 FILE: IMGP0028-2021-05-05-20-45.JPG @2021-04-28 20:45
 FILE: IMGP0023-2021-05-05-20-45.JPG @2021-04-28 20:45
 FILE: IMGP0022-2021-05-05-20-45.JPG @2021-04-28 20:45
 FILE: IMGP0021-2021-05-05-20-45.JPG @2021-04-28 20:45
 FILE: IMGP0020-2021-05-05-20-45.JPG @2021-04-28 20:45
 FILE: IMGP0015-2021-05-05-20-45.JPG @2021-04-28 20:45
 FILE: IMGP0013-2021-05-05-20-45.JPG @2021-04-28 20:45
 FILE: IMGP0012-2021-05-05-20-45.JPG @2021-04-28 20:45
 FILE: IMGP0010-2021-05-05-20-45.JPG @2021-04-28 20:45
 4/27 Flew back to Kobe. Train to Wakayama port, then ferry home. I dropped my camera on the way but some kind person found it and keep it in the station @2021-04-28 15:35
 4/25 Biked over a mountain to Dynamic Lab in Minami-satsuma City.  Met Tender. I asked him many questions and got clear answeres to many of those. non-electric, systems-thinking, nvc,  I have to write about this separately. @2021-04-28 15:33)</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 20:49:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-04-19</title><description>(Father took me to onsen. @2021-04-19 16:02
 Afternoon. Continue cleaning up kitchen. @2021-04-19 16:02
 Ate sandwich at cafe in the train station. @2021-04-19 16:01
 Went by the tram to Kagoshima-chuo to buy kizami. Then I went to ishin-museum. @2021-04-19 16:01)</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 16:02:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-04-18</title><description>(父は動画編集用にデスクトップPCを組んでいた。 @2021-04-18 15:14
 昨夜父が話していた大和三算(切算、裏算、重算)について、あやしいYoutuberの情報しか出てこないが、ちゃんとした情報を見てみたい。 @2021-04-18 15:13
 Installed mpg123 on raspi to make it stream internet radio. @2021-04-18 15:12
 壊れた目ざまし時計から採ったタクトスイッチをraspberry piのRUNにはんだづけして、ソフトリセットスイッチにした。Sigmarionとシリアル通信中、ハングしてどうしようもなくなる時があり、電源を抜くとSDのデータとOSが壊れる可能性がある悩みが一応解決。SunDiskの産業用microSDも注文した。 @2021-04-18 15:10
 夕飯(blackcoff=父): かぼちゃ、しいたけ、豚肉の煮物, 味噌汁, 米飯. 　味付けを習った。しょうゆ、みりん、半量の酒、砂糖大匙1足らず @2021-04-18 15:05
 昼飯のお米を炊こうと思ったら、台所があまりにも汚すぎたので、お米を炊きながら掃除を開始。父がキャベツと豚肉いためと味噌汁をつくって、昼飯。その後掃除の続き。ゴミと古い液体類を処分していった。ごみためになっていた一角は終わった。 @2021-04-18 15:01
 買い物中、やむをえない場合を除き、プラスチック包装されていないものを選んで買ったら、いいものが集まった。封筒、歯ブラシ、油揚げ、ふきん、裁縫糸は、プラスチック包装されたものしか置いていなかった。 @2021-04-18 14:58
 Went to Taiyo super market and bought pairs of apples, tomatoes, and potatoes, a cabbage, an onion, 油揚げ, block bacon, ハヤシライスのもと, 2 small cans of beer. JPY1355. @2021-04-18 14:56
 Went to Nafco and bought slippers and socks. @2021-04-18 14:53
 Went to off-house/hard-off.  So many good stuff. I found male usb-mini-A to usb socket cable.  This is supposed to be extremely rare and exactly what I needed to use the usb-host on Sigmarion III. I also bought a small passive coca-cola speaker, and a ladies indigo shirt. @2021-04-18 14:52
 BOUGHT: toothbrush with platinum lining, thin polyester apron, a pair of rubber grip gloves, thin cotton 手拭い, 亀の子たわし, small can of anti-rust yellow paint, small glass bottle of paint thinner, paint brush, thick envelopes, kitchen towel, sawing string (poly-ester oh-no. I wanted cotton.), too small thin rubber gloves.  JPY3114. @2021-04-18 14:47
 HANDSMANに行った。ガラスの天井の巨大な空間に木や植物が植わっていて、まるで植物園のよう。品数もものすごい。こんなホームセンターははじめて見た。 Went to DIY shop HANDSMAN. Huge space inside has a glass ceiling and the space is covered with vegetation. Wow! @2021-04-18 14:37
 朝、おばあちゃんとしゃべった。みのりちゃんのことを覚えていて、涙をにじませて喜んでくれた。 Spoke to grandma. She asked who I am many times throughout the day but each time she did remember me and seemed glad seeing me. @2021-04-18 14:31)</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2021 15:14:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-04-17</title><description>(Spoke to おばあちゃん. She does not recognize me.  @2021-04-17 15:25
 Sakurajima ferry to Kagoshima-city. Train. Father came to pick me up.  おじさんcame and us 3 went out for dinner. @2021-04-17 15:20
 Took bus to Sakurajima-port. Got off on the way to take a look around.  Talked to a local おじいちゃん.  Took photos of 小学校. Washed my hair with sea water. @2021-04-17 15:16
 ate at とんぼラーメン @2021-04-17 15:11
 Arrived in Shibushi port. Connected raspi to public wifi and got info about transportation around Kagoshima.  Took the bus to Tarumizu port. JPY 1280 @2021-04-17 15:11
 Ferry one-way JPY 8,660. Round-trip 10,000 @2021-04-17 15:10
 Slept in the ferry and had a strange dream.  Woke up and took a bath. @2021-04-17 15:08)</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 15:25:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-04-15</title><description>(house-(bus)-&gt;tokushima-(bus)-&gt;osaka-(train)-&gt;port town-(ferry)-&gt; @2021-04-15 17:52
  @2021-04-15 17:48
 Installed shortblog to raspberry pi. This post is written on sig3 and sent via ttyUSB through raspi. @2021-04-15 17:36
 Succeed in setting up Sigmarion III &lt;---&gt; Raspberry PI &lt;---&gt; Internet!  It lets  travel much lighter :)  @2021-04-15 17:34)</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 17:52:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-04-30</title><description>(今日でPILOT退職。昨日ビデオレターを撮って送った。 @2021-04-30 19:57
 masato wants a scale that shows how much the price of onion for a given person calculated based on the number of times he/she participated. @2021-04-30 19:56
 しいたけこまつけ with Kta + mayukobe @2021-04-30 19:54)</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 19:58:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-04-15</title><description>(FILE: IMGP0003-2021-04-15-21-36.JPG @2021-04-15 21:36
 FILE: IMGP0009-2021-04-15-21-36.JPG @2021-04-15 21:36
 FILE: IMGP0008-2021-04-15-21-36.JPG @2021-04-15 21:36
 FILE: IMGP0007-2021-04-15-21-36.JPG @2021-04-15 21:36
 FILE: IMGP0005-2021-04-15-21-36.JPG @2021-04-15 21:36
 FILE: IMGP0072-2021-04-15-21-36.JPG @2021-04-15 21:36
 FILE: IMGP0069-2021-04-15-21-36.JPG @2021-04-15 21:36
 FILE: IMGP0068-2021-04-15-21-35.JPG @2021-04-15 21:35
 SCRIPT: sudo getty -L ttyUSB0 9600 vt102 #run this on the linux machine. @2021-04-15 20:28
 posting from 24term on Sigmarion III connected to Bodhi Linux on Thinkpad. @2021-04-15 20:26
 天、初めての保育所。海が教室まで連れて行ってくれて、泣かずに入れた。おやつも食べて外でも元気に遊んだよう。家に帰ってくると、ぐずって智にくっついてから、一人はしゃいでいた。頭の中の世界で遊んでいるみたい。 @2021-04-15 12:52)</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 21:36:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-04-14</title><description>(Read a book about Adler's individual psychology. @2021-04-14 21:50
 Read TOEC parents journal. @2021-04-14 21:46
 Drinking beer right before sleep seem to make me wake up with clear feeling after oversleeping. @2021-04-14 21:40
 夜はたけのこご飯とホウボウの干物と菊芋のきんぴら。(智) @2021-04-14 21:36
 昼飯は雪ノ下の天ぷらと梅つゆそうめん @2021-04-14 21:36
 FARM: 庭の菜園に種まき。菊芋、つるなしインゲン、スナップエンドウ、枝豆、人参、レタスミックス、謎黒豆。 @2021-04-14 21:35
 TODO: link urls @2021-04-14 00:30)</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 21:50:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-04-13</title><description>(鹿児島までの旅客一人あたりのCO2排出量計算、http://tco2.com によると、飛行機でKIXからKOJまで片道52kg。コロナで乗客数が減ることを考慮するとこれ以上だろう。http://www.jlc-ferry.jp によるとフェリーで大阪南港から志布志まで片道24kg。新幹線はべらぼうに低排出だが、電力は原発依存だろうし、切符がべらぼうに高い。飛行機とフェリーは飛行機のほうが安いが桁は同じ。というわけでフェリーで行くことにしようと思う。 @2021-04-13 23:59
 蚊がたくさん出てきた。 @2021-04-13 23:50 髭を剃った @2021-04-13 23:49
 町の計画に則って、鮎喰川の放流鮎を守るために、天然の川鵜を散弾銃で射殺している人と出会った。岩に留まった鵜を狙っていたが、鵜が飛んでから発砲、鵜は飛び去って、その後見失っていた。　町の計画(昨年度)→　https://www.town.kamiyama.lg.jp/office/sangyouenjoy/image/R2%E8%A2%AB%E5%AE%B3%E9%98%B2%E6%AD%A2%E8%A8%88%E7%94%BB%EF%BC%88%E4%BD%90%E9%82%A3%E6%B2%B3%E5%86%85%E7%A5%9E%E5%B1%B1%EF%BC%89.pdf　これによると、被害想定額は45万円。30羽を射殺する計画なので、一羽あたりの命の値段は1万5千円。 @2021-04-13 23:47)</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 23:59:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-04-12</title><description>(set viewport @2021-04-12 22:14 TODO: plant lettuces @2021-04-12 22:07
 退職時の諸手続きについて、CNAさんと通話。年金、健康保険などの切り替えについて、提出物、返却物など。 @2021-04-12 21:41
 sketch by sea @2021-04-12 21:36
 FILE: IMGP0065-2021-04-12-21-35.JPG @2021-04-12 21:35)</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 22:14:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-04-11</title><description>(家にいる時間が長いと、頭が正常に働かない感じが強い。今、この場所、以外のことを考えようとすると、ご飯が作れないときのような、思考に靄がかかったような、無気力でなにもできない感じがする。 @2021-04-11 20:35
 Drew mazes w/ sea. She starts to get the rules. @2021-04-11 20:27)</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 20:35:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-04-09</title><description>(Ate beans curry for dinner. Called Rina and we all spoke in turn. @2021-04-09 21:57
 Went stroling late afternoon with sea on her bike and sky on her anpanman-car. Sea insists she goes to her friends house so we did.  They weren't there. We parked the bike+car and walked home (sky on my back). @2021-04-09 21:55
 畑土作り。ツルハシで起こしたゴロゴロ土にキエーロの中のふかふか土を混ぜて、草をかぶせて、ブルーシートをかけた。 @2021-04-09 21:53
 昼前、初の活元運動。動画を見て感じを掴んで準備運動2回目で出た。面白い！ @2021-04-09 21:52
 クーポンで智がお寿司を買ってきて、食べた。智昼寝。 @2021-04-09 21:48
 Woke up at 2AM. Cooked 朝ごはん while listening to the radio. 人参フライ、オニオンリング、味噌マリネ、梅酢蓮根粥。粥は朝は人気がなかった。パンがあったから。人参フライ美味しい。その後朝寝。 @2021-04-09 21:47
 FILE: IMGP0059-2021-04-09-21-43.JPG @2021-04-09 21:43
 FILE: IMGP0058-2021-04-09-21-43.JPG @2021-04-09 21:43
 FILE: IMGP0057-2021-04-09-21-43.JPG @2021-04-09 21:43
 FILE: IMGP0056-2021-04-09-21-43.JPG @2021-04-09 21:43
 FILE: IMGP0061-2021-04-09-21-43.JPG @2021-04-09 21:43
 FILE: IMGP0055-2021-04-09-21-46.JPG @2021-04-09 21:46)</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 21:57:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-04-08</title><description>(SCHEDULE: 月曜日16時よりcna-sanと映話。退職について。 @2021-04-08 21:34
 FILE: IMGP0053-2021-04-08-21-15.JPG @2021-04-08 21:15
 夜飯(実)→蓮根と玉ねぎの梅酢サラダ(蓮根は梅酢と水で少し煮る)、冷奴、白飯、ハゲみりん干しとサヨリ焼き魚。天は色々食べたが最後にさよりの頭を食べて吐いた。あとから蓮根梅酢煮汁でおかゆをして少し食べた。 @2021-04-08 21:12
 10時頃神山整体に電話。3時から予約。2時半にカブで出発。聞いたこと→左側の脊柱起立筋が緊張している。全身に緊張が溜まっている。頚椎2番の左が下に落ちていた。左骨盤が内に締まっていた。活元運動をすると良い。感じたこと→優しく色々な箇所を押したり引いたり揺らしたりしてもらううちに、緩んでいく感じがあった。両額に手をかざした時、左の三叉神経痛に悩まされている部位がジワーッと感応していた。 @2021-04-08 21:08
 智、鳴門へ大谷焼を買いに。大皿、茶碗、魚皿、湯呑み、匙など買ってきた。実は朝寝。 @2021-04-08 20:56)</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 21:34:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-04-07</title><description>(FARM: Planted pumpkin seeds in the second garden. Maybe it's better to let it sprout in a pot.  The seeds are from pumpkins we ate last year. Dried and stored in a shade but w/ no cover. @2021-04-07 20:23
 Went to look at the earthbag dome building process. Then shopping, then to Seibu park, then to curry. @2021-04-07 20:04
 FILE: IMGP0049-2021-04-07-20-02.JPG @2021-04-07 20:02
 FILE: IMGP0047-2021-04-07-20-02.JPG @2021-04-07 20:02
 FILE: IMGP0046-2021-04-07-20-02.JPG @2021-04-07 20:02
 FILE: IMGP0044-2021-04-07-20-02.JPG @2021-04-07 20:02
 FILE: IMGP0042-2021-04-07-20-02.JPG @2021-04-07 20:02
 FILE: IMGP0041-2021-04-07-20-02.JPG @2021-04-07 20:02
 FILE: IMGP0036-2021-04-07-20-01.JPG @2021-04-07 20:01
 FILE: IMGP0034-2021-04-07-20-01.JPG @2021-04-07 20:01)</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 20:23:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-04-06</title><description>(イーガン『しあわせの理由』表題作がまるで自分のことのようだった。 @2021-04-06 21:19
 ホウボウの干物がふっくらしていてめちゃ旨い。 @2021-04-06 21:15 マグネシウム粒届いた。 @2021-04-06 21:14
 昼、智、海帰宅。私は寝る。肩がどうも捻挫というか肉離れ的な状態らしく、安静にしておく必要がある。 @2021-04-06 21:14
 午前中、今日も天と留守番。少し遠くまで散歩に行く。帰り道、白線から出たらだめと言うと泣く。何度も。自由にさせてあげたいけど車が走り回る道沿いに住んでいる限り、ちゃんと教えないと。文明が嫌になるのはこういう時。狼や熊に怯えなくていい代わりに殺傷力を持った乗り物つまり戦車に怯えなければいけない。 @2021-04-06 21:12)</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 21:19:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-04-05</title><description>(洗濯用マグネシウム粒注文した @2021-04-05 21:10
 夕方、楽刈り鎌使いづらいと思っていたが、刃を外側に曲げたら良くなった。 @2021-04-05 21:08
 cnaさんにメールした @2021-04-05 21:06 夜(智)　スパゲッティ、具は昼と同じ。色々な塩味 @2021-04-05 21:04
 帰りしな、無人販売のはっさくを買いたかったけど失敗。酒屋でビールと甘酒を買った。 @2021-04-05 21:03
 『富士日記』面白い。 @2021-04-05 21:02
 自転車でホームセンターへ。登り鎌がおいていない。代わりに頼まれたペンキとアングル、刷毛を買って帰る。途中古墳で休憩。 @2021-04-05 20:51
 昼ご飯、マカロニに人参玉ねぎキャベツアンチョビ炒めまぶし、レンズ豆煮豆。@2021-04-05 20:47
 ２月頃作った滑り台初公開。５年間机として使っていた材をリメイクした。 @2021-04-05 20:47
 FILE: IMGP0031-2021-04-05-20-46.JPG @2021-04-05 20:46
 FILE: IMGP0026-2021-04-05-20-46.JPG @2021-04-05 20:46
 FILE: IMGP0025-2021-04-05-20-46.JPG @2021-04-05 20:46
 海は保育所へ。智は耳鼻科へ。天と留守番。小雨散歩。桜の花弁が吹かれて溜まっている。天、保育所に入りたそう。 @2021-04-05 20:44
 朝、６次起床。経費精算と勤怠入力。これがほとんど最後かと思うとなんだか切ないような気持ちだった。 @2021-04-05 20:42)</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 21:10:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-04-04</title><description>(went to onsen and felt so good @2021-04-04 20:21
 lets halt X when I don't need it @2021-04-04 16:49
 TODO: communication w/ pilotz @2021-04-04 16:47
 S saying we have to fix the plan for Kagoshima trip. @2021-04-04 16:47
 father writing blog about marketing of gardening work online. @2021-04-04 16:46
 sea wants to play with mayui. she started walking by herself so I followed and gave her a bike ride.  went to hon-no-hiroba with k/m/m. we came to my house later and just let kids play. k said he needs to go home w/ m. sea cried and tells me she wants to play more. @2021-04-04 16:45
 morning- cut weeds in gardens. put out some garbage @2021-04-04 16:42)</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 20:21:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-04-03</title><description>NIL</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 14:00:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-04-02</title><description>(海がスマーフみたいでなにかにつけやんちゃだった。 @2021-04-02 20:41
 Sが獲った三角錐の貝が美味しかった。 @2021-04-02 20:36
 Sの運転で南へ保養に連れて行ってくれた。海の波が砕ける音が聞こえるのは最高。温泉に入ってもストレッチしても左肩と左首が滅茶苦茶重かったが、Sのヨガで直った。後ろで手を組む牛のポーズがよく効く。ちゃんと前を向く事とか、順序とか、呼吸が大事。帰りは車で体が痛かったので一人途中リタイアして電車とバスで帰ってきた。 @2021-04-02 20:25
 FILE: IMGP0016-2021-04-02-20-17.JPG @2021-04-02 20:17
 FILE: IMGP0015-2021-04-02-20-16.JPG @2021-04-02 20:16
 FILE: IMGP0009-2021-04-02-20-16.JPG @2021-04-02 20:16
 FILE: IMGP0007-2021-04-02-20-16.JPG @2021-04-02 20:16
 FILE: IMGP0006-2021-04-02-20-16.JPG @2021-04-02 20:16
 FILE: IMGP0004-2021-04-02-20-16.JPG @2021-04-02 20:16
 FILE: IMGP0001-2021-04-02-20-16.JPG @2021-04-02 20:16
 FILE: IMGP0108-2021-04-02-20-16.JPG @2021-04-02 20:16
 FILE: IMGP0102-2021-04-02-20-15.JPG @2021-04-02 20:15
 FILE: IMGP0100-2021-04-02-20-15.JPG @2021-04-02 20:15
 FILE: IMGP0099-2021-04-02-20-15.JPG @2021-04-02 20:15
 FILE: IMGP0092-2021-04-02-20-15.JPG @2021-04-02 20:15
 FILE: IMGP0089-2021-04-02-20-17.JPG @2021-04-02 20:17
 FILE: IMGP0086-2021-04-02-20-15.JPG @2021-04-02 20:15
 FILE: IMGP0082-2021-04-02-20-14.JPG @2021-04-02 20:14)</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 20:41:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-03-30</title><description>(watching kids while S goes working. It is nice to work on the little farm while kids play in the school ground right next. trying to die some masks and tenugui with yomogi @2021-03-30 10:35)</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 10:35:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-03-29</title><description>(The nerves in the left upper part of my body still aches quite a bit. @2021-03-29 21:23
 Oda fam and Yuki-san came and we held Original Play session with mainly local kids + parents.  I didn't help much in the advertising phase so I took responsibility in mediating between us and the people in charge of the venue. Overall, great time.  @2021-03-29 21:23
 FILE: IMGP0066-2021-04-02-20-13.JPG @2021-03-29 20:13
 FILE: IMGP0061-2021-04-02-20-13.JPG @2021-03-29 20:13
 FILE: IMGP0058-2021-04-02-20-13.JPG @2021-03-29 20:13
 FILE: IMGP0057-2021-04-02-20-13.JPG @2021-03-29 20:13
 FILE: IMGP0049-2021-04-02-20-13.JPG @2021-03-29 20:13
 In the morning potatos from last year covered in ash got planted in the second garden. @2021-03-29 21:14)</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 21:26:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-03-28</title><description>NIL</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 21:33:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-03-27</title><description>(Went to common to pick up the cub. Met air playing outside by himself. I played with him. He found kiji bird and thinks it's a kujaku.  We made bazooka from bamboo together. @2021-03-27 18:54
 昨日の砂利運びの影響で肩と首が痛い。 @2021-03-27 18:52
 野舞台一斉清掃+お花見+襖からくり練習。Sは弁当屋に行くので、子供と参加。最初少し掃除して、あとは自由に過ごした。2年ぶりの集まりで海は色んな人と交歓していた。襖からくり練習で、初めて吊り下げを担当した。思っていたより3倍重かった。2回やって、2回目はうまくできた。初めて操作をする人もいて、上手くなっていた。またここに皆で集まれて良かった。Oさんありがとう。 @2021-03-27 18:51
 FILE: IMGP0039-2021-03-27-18-43.JPG @2021-03-27 18:43
 FILE: IMGP0038-2021-03-27-18-43.JPG @2021-03-27 18:43
 FILE: IMGP0037-2021-03-27-18-43.JPG @2021-03-27 18:43
 FILE: IMGP0036-2021-03-27-18-43.JPG @2021-03-27 18:43
 FILE: IMGP0035-2021-03-27-18-43.JPG @2021-03-27 18:43
 FILE: IMGP0034-2021-03-27-18-43.JPG @2021-03-27 18:43
 FILE: IMGP0033-2021-03-27-18-43.JPG @2021-03-27 18:43
 FILE: IMGP0031-2021-03-27-18-43.JPG @2021-03-27 18:43
 FILE: IMGP0030-2021-03-27-18-43.JPG @2021-03-27 18:43
 FILE: IMGP0027-2021-03-27-18-43.JPG @2021-03-27 18:43
 FILE: IMGP0026-2021-03-27-18-43.JPG @2021-03-27 18:43
 FILE: IMGP0025-2021-03-27-18-43.JPG @2021-03-27 18:43
 FILE: IMGP0022-2021-03-27-18-42.JPG @2021-03-27 18:42
 FILE: IMGP0021-2021-03-27-18-42.JPG @2021-03-27 18:42
 FILE: IMGP0020-2021-03-27-18-42.JPG @2021-03-27 18:42
 FILE: IMGP0019-2021-03-27-18-42.JPG @2021-03-27 18:42
 FILE: IMGP0018-2021-03-27-18-42.JPG @2021-03-27 18:42
 FILE: IMGP0016-2021-03-27-18-42.JPG @2021-03-27 18:42
 FILE: IMGP0015-2021-03-27-18-42.JPG @2021-03-27 18:42
 FILE: IMGP0014-2021-03-27-18-42.JPG @2021-03-27 18:42
 FILE: IMGP0013-2021-03-27-18-42.JPG @2021-03-27 18:42
 FILE: IMGP0012-2021-03-27-18-42.JPG @2021-03-27 18:42
 FILE: IMGP0011-2021-03-27-18-42.JPG @2021-03-27 18:42
 FILE: IMGP0010-2021-03-27-18-42.JPG @2021-03-27 18:42
 FILE: IMGP0009-2021-03-27-18-42.JPG @2021-03-27 18:42
 FILE: IMGP0008-2021-03-27-18-42.JPG @2021-03-27 18:42
 FILE: IMGP0006-2021-03-27-18-42.JPG @2021-03-27 18:42)</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 18:54:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-03-26</title><description>(On the way home Keita shared with me his plan for connecting gardening work and handicapped people. I very much resonate with that idea.  I think that will make many people happy. @2021-03-26 20:34
 Garden work with Kimisorganics and Mankitsuya.  Carrying the gravel bags was heavy on my back but I enjoyed working with them, earth, dirt, roots, and grass. It was a hot day.  @2021-03-26 20:33
 FILE: IMGP0146-2021-03-26-20-22.JPG @2021-03-26 20:22
 FILE: IMGP0145-2021-03-26-20-22.JPG @2021-03-26 20:22
 FILE: IMGP0142-2021-03-26-20-22.JPG @2021-03-26 20:22
 FILE: IMGP0141-2021-03-26-20-22.JPG @2021-03-26 20:22
 FILE: IMGP0140-2021-03-26-20-22.JPG @2021-03-26 20:22
 FILE: IMGP0138-2021-03-26-20-21.JPG @2021-03-26 20:21
 FILE: IMGP0137-2021-03-26-20-21.JPG @2021-03-26 20:21
 FILE: IMGP0134-2021-03-26-20-21.JPG @2021-03-26 20:21)</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 20:34:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-03-25</title><description>(トレラン、こりす担当。天は最初元気に、海は帰り道楽しく走れた。 @2021-03-25 22:51
 6 breaths/minute 迷走神経 activation @2021-03-25 14:46
 疲れたら出てくる左眼周りの顔面痛が治らず、4ヶ月ぶりに耳鼻科に行った。レントゲンを取り、副鼻腔は問題なく神経痛だろうと診断。薬は貰わず。1.5kの窓口負担。鼻のことはちょくちょく鼻うがいでもしよう。神経痛は無理をせず休憩するようにしよう. @2021-03-25 14:46
 3/24 カブ旅. 鳴門へ。お惣菜屋さんでコッヘルにカレーを入れてもらった。少しだけ釣りをしてみたけど釣れなかった。道の駅第九の里から会社の代表に電話をかけ辞意を伝えた。次の瞬間父からメールが来た。電話をして、その後荷が降りたのかボーっとしてしまった。 @2021-03-25 14:39
 FILE: IMGP0133-2021-03-25-14-33.JPG @2021-03-25 14:33
 FILE: IMGP0132-2021-03-25-14-33.JPG @2021-03-25 14:33
 FILE: IMGP0128-2021-03-25-14-33.JPG @2021-03-25 14:33
 FILE: IMGP0127-2021-03-25-14-33.JPG @2021-03-25 14:33
 FILE: IMGP0125-2021-03-25-14-33.JPG @2021-03-25 14:33
 FILE: IMGP0124-2021-03-25-14-32.JPG @2021-03-25 14:32
 FILE: IMGP0122-2021-03-25-14-32.JPG @2021-03-25 14:32)</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 22:53:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-03-23</title><description>(呉服店で和手拭いを２枚買った。白に紺の柄入り。よもぎ染めしてみたい。 @2021-03-23 23:22
 HIGHLIGHT: (海)ビー玉がなかったのでどんぐりと梅干しの種を丸く削って遊んだ。削っていたら、もっとなにか作りたくなって、前から作ろうと思っていたドミノ倒し用の牌を作った。杉の桟木なので柔らかすぎるし目も詰まっていないし軽すぎるけど、加工は簡単。ノミで杢目に沿って上手にパキパキ割って、紙やすりでツルツルにしていた。完璧なものよりも今遊びたいけどないから作っちゃおうというのが大事。 @2021-03-23 23:10
 (天)アンパンマン号で散歩。その後保育所に歩いていって、入りたそうにしていた。そしてまたアンパンマン号で川の向こうの商店まで行って帰ってきた。はっさくを買って２個食べた。近所のおばあちゃんと久しぶりに喋った。 @2021-03-23 23:03
 FILE: IMGP0120-2021-03-23-22-56.JPG @2021-03-23 22:56
 FILE: IMGP0117-2021-03-23-22-55.JPG @2021-03-23 22:55
 stayed home with sky. Went out many times. Sun is warm. Met many grandmas @2021-03-23 12:43
 3/22 went to the park with sky, sea @2021-03-23 12:42
 3/22 trail running @2021-03-23 12:41
 FILE: IMGP0098-2021-03-23-12-01.JPG @2021-03-23 12:01
 FILE: IMGP0088-2021-03-23-12-01.JPG @2021-03-23 12:01
 FILE: IMGP0083-2021-03-23-12-00.JPG @2021-03-23 12:00
 FILE: IMGP0081-2021-03-23-12-00.JPG @2021-03-23 12:00
 FILE: IMGP0071-2021-03-23-11-59.JPG @2021-03-23 11:59
 FILE: IMGP0073-2021-03-23-11-59.JPG @2021-03-23 11:59
 FILE: IMGP0074-2021-03-23-11-58.JPG @2021-03-23 11:58
 FILE: IMGP0070-2021-03-23-11-55.JPG @2021-03-23 11:55)</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 23:22:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-03-21</title><description>(Finally emailed Benoit. @2021-03-21 15:18
 listening to bbc crowdscience @2021-03-21 15:17
 went to monostock and bought a wooden box to put on the back of the cub @2021-03-21 13:29)</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 15:18:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-03-20</title><description>(went for a little walk and found a nice tree to climb @2021-03-20 16:22
 FILE: IMGP0069-2021-03-20-16-22.JPG @2021-03-20 16:22
 FILE: IMGP0068-2021-03-20-16-22.JPG @2021-03-20 16:22
 FILE: IMGP0067-2021-03-20-16-22.JPG @2021-03-20 16:22
 DEV(shortblog): style a little bit @2021-03-20 12:08
 FILE: Screen Shot 2021-03-20 at 12.06.50-2021-03-20-12-08.png @2021-03-20 12:08
 DEV(shortblog): make html structure better @2021-03-20 12:05)</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 16:22:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-03-19</title><description>(shortblog now generates rss feed but it needs improvement @2021-03-19 23:27
 PLANTSのチラシを配った。ブッダカフェ、コンプレックス、豆ちよ、改善センター、作良家、丸池商店など @2021-03-19 23:26
 3/18 trail running with kids.  staff: mio, kocchan. loved kocchan's cookies @2021-03-19 10:28
 3/18 自主保育。焚き火でご飯と味噌汁を炊いていたら隣のおばあさんに苦情を言われる。 @2021-03-19 10:27
 FILE: IMGP0064-2021-03-19-10-26.JPG @2021-03-19 10:26
 FILE: IMGP0063-2021-03-19-10-26.JPG @2021-03-19 10:26
 FILE: IMGP0062-2021-03-19-10-26.JPG @2021-03-19 10:26
 FILE: IMGP0061-2021-03-19-10-26.JPG @2021-03-19 10:26
 FILE: IMGP0060-2021-03-19-10-26.JPG @2021-03-19 10:26
 FILE: IMGP0059-2021-03-19-10-26.JPG @2021-03-19 24:00)</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 23:27:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-03-17</title><description>(battery -&gt; cub. The battery was dead so I charged it with solar with a deep cycle battery in parallel. Hopefully it recovers. @2021-03-17 21:09
 FILE: IMGP0050.JPG @2021-03-17 21:07
 家族で味噌作り。焚き火で豆を炊いて、潰して、米麹と塩を入れて混ぜて、壺に投げつける。いい陽気であった。 @2021-03-17 21:06
 FILE: IMGP0058.JPG @2021-03-17 21:04 FILE: IMGP0057.JPG @2021-03-17 21:04
 FILE: IMGP0056.JPG @2021-03-17 21:04 FILE: IMGP0055.JPG @2021-03-17 21:03
 FILE: IMGP0053.JPG @2021-03-17 21:03 FILE: IMGP0052.JPG @2021-03-17 21:03
 FILE: IMGP0044.JPG @2021-03-17 21:02 FILE: IMGP0043.JPG @2021-03-17 21:02
 FILE: IMGP0041-2021-03-17-21:19.JPG @2021-03-17 21:19
 FILE: IMGP0040-2021-03-17-21:19.JPG @2021-03-17 21:19
 FILE: IMGP0039-2021-03-17-21:19.JPG @2021-03-17 21:19
 FILE: IMGP0038-2021-03-17-21:18.JPG @2021-03-17 21:18
 HAIKU: 母からの荷物は紅茶ときらず揚げ @2021-03-17 12:54
 HAIKU: 焚火湯で淹れる薄めの熱コーヒー @2021-03-17 12:50
 HAIKU: 萌え草や古木が煙り豆煮える @2021-03-17 12:49
 I worked a bit too much on SHORTBLOG last night. I couldn't wake up in the morning. I have to limit myself. @2021-03-17 11:22
 SHORTBLOG now generates index page @2021-03-17 11:20)</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 21:09:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-03-16</title><description>(sbcl独自拡張の外部プログラム呼び出しでimagemagickを呼んで、サムネイルを生成するようにした。 @2021-03-16 23:30
 バイク修理後小神子海岸に釣りに行った。穴釣り用の竿はチョイ投げに向いていない。チョイ投げ用の竿が欲しい。釣果0匹 @2021-03-16 21:39
 徳島スーパーカブでリアタイアの交換を依頼。丁寧に見てくれて、チェーンも交換してくれた。今まで悩みの種だった、走行中の周期的な引っかかったような揺れが消失。とても調子が良くなった。自賠責が切れていたので手続きして、2年分登録した。 @2021-03-16 21:38
 FILE: IMGP0032.JPG @2021-03-16 21:35 FILE: IMGP0031.JPG @2021-03-16 21:34
 FILE: IMGP0030.JPG @2021-03-16 12:25 _shinzennin_ @2021-03-16 12:21
 MAINTENANCE: Changed engine oil for the cub at 286667km. @2021-03-16 12:20
 I made a solar wall. It works. TODO: put duct fan. place it on the roof. @2021-03-16 12:19
 yesterday sea, sky and me went to mori-no-hi. good time. @2021-03-16 12:18
 FILE: IMGP0029.JPG @2021-03-16 12:16 FILE: IMGP0028.JPG @2021-03-16 12:16
 FILE: IMGP0027.JPG @2021-03-16 12:16 FILE: IMGP0026.JPG @2021-03-16 12:16)</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 23:30:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-03-14</title><description>(TODO: imagemagick thumbnail generation. be sure to strip exif @2021-03-14 22:16
 Made a CLI interface for miniblog using buildapp. Now I can do `shortblog make-post &quot;blah blah&quot;`, `shortblog add-media &quot;/mnt/DCIM/xxx/yyy.JPG&quot;`, etc. It even outputs help messages when error occures. @2021-03-14 22:06
 FILE: IMGP0025.JPG @2021-03-14 21:55 FILE: IMGP0024.JPG @2021-03-14 21:55
 FILE: IMGP0023.JPG @2021-03-14 21:55 FILE: IMGP0022.JPG @2021-03-14 21:55
 FILE: IMGP0021.JPG @2021-03-14 21:55 FILE: IMGP0020.JPG @2021-03-14 21:55
 FILE: IMGP0019.JPG @2021-03-14 21:55 FILE: IMGP0018.JPG @2021-03-14 21:55
 FILE: IMGP0017.JPG @2021-03-14 21:55 FILE: IMGP0016.JPG @2021-03-14 21:55
 FILE: IMGP0015.JPG @2021-03-14 21:55 FILE: IMGP0014.JPG @2021-03-14 21:55
 FILE: IMGP0013.JPG @2021-03-14 21:55 FILE: IMGP0012.JPG @2021-03-14 21:55
 カメラを落としてきたので一度帰ってからもう一度カブで登って探しに行った。見つかった記念に一枚。 @2021-03-14 21:52
 その後、海、天と森林公園へ。ポテレット広場で延々と遊ぶ。 @2021-03-14 21:51
 朝、家族で鎌田さん家に行く。脱穀したそばの唐箕がけ。お好み焼きを焼いてくれた。2013年の梅酒が美味しい。 @2021-03-14 21:50
 cli interface test @2021-03-14 20:46
 昨日夕方Super cubのカウルとミラーを交換。旭風防のショートバイザーを取り付けた。試しに山城まで走る。リアタイヤが減っている。 @2021-03-14 08:23
 FILE: IMGP0011.JPG @2021-03-14 08:22)</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 22:16:00 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-03-12</title><description>(FILE: shot-2021-03-12_22-15-14.jpg @2021-03-12 22:25:40
 miniblogのhtml生成機能を作った。WTFPLで90行のhtml-&gt;stringを使った。quasiquoteとunquoteで制御できて単純便利。写真の公開制御なにかうまいこと考えついたらgithub pagesで公開したい。 @2021-03-12 22:23
 Bike to Komatsushima and bought 5 packets of ukon. I then went to fishing shop and bought a short telescopic rod+reel. I wanted to go to the harbor to fish but the rain became severe so I biked home. @2021-03-12 20:34:56)</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 22:25:40 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-03-11</title><description>(went to Naruto with friends to hunt wakame @2021-03-11 22:30:36
 FILE: IMGP0010.JPG @2021-03-11 22:29:41
 FILE: IMGP0009.JPG @2021-03-11 22:29:41
 FILE: IMGP0008.JPG @2021-03-11 22:29:41
 FILE: IMGP0007.JPG @2021-03-11 22:29:41
 FILE: IMGP0006.JPG @2021-03-11 22:29:41
 FILE: IMGP0005.JPG @2021-03-11 22:29:41)</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 22:30:36 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-03-10</title><description>(TODO: draw net-zero-office-plan and send it to Inobe-san @2021-03-10 18:46:50
 SCHEDULE: 3/27 Ono-sakura-nobutai moritsukuri @2021-03-10 18:45:49
 ordered glassfiber mesh online @2021-03-10 18:45:03
 SCRIPT: for f in /mnt/DCIM/XXX/*.JPG; do sbcl --core miniblog --eval &quot;(miniblog::add-media \&quot;$f\&quot;)&quot; --quit; done @2021-03-10 18:39:40
 FILE: IMGP0042.JPG @2021-03-10 18:33:59
 FILE: IMGP0041.JPG @2021-03-10 18:33:58
 FILE: IMGP0040.JPG @2021-03-10 18:33:58
 FILE: IMGP0039.JPG @2021-03-10 18:33:58
 FILE: IMGP0038.JPG @2021-03-10 18:33:58
 FILE: IMGP0037.JPG @2021-03-10 18:33:58
 FILE: IMGP0036.JPG @2021-03-10 18:33:58
 FILE: IMGP0035.JPG @2021-03-10 18:33:58
 Photos from yesterday:  @2021-03-10 18:33:49
 drove to Konan-Pro to get materials for solar wall! @2021-03-10 18:33:20
 FILE: IMGP0004.JPG @2021-03-10 18:30:11
 FILE: IMGP0003.JPG @2021-03-10 18:30:11
 FILE: IMGP0002.JPG @2021-03-10 18:30:10
 FILE: IMGP0001.JPG @2021-03-10 18:30:10
 went to hatakeno-hi to borrow car from satoco @2021-03-10 18:28:18)</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 18:46:50 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-03-09</title><description>(FILE: IMGP0034.JPG @2021-03-09 08:41:13
 FILE: IMGP0033.JPG @2021-03-09 08:41:11
 planted the kaki tree Keita and I dag yesterday in the garden @2021-03-09 08:34:34)</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 08:41:13 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-03-08</title><description>(net sync ホワイトボード @2021-03-08 21:01:13
 It's good that I work a little with computer again @2021-03-08 21:00:48
 I have to find my way back to working with electronics @2021-03-08 20:58:55
 TODO: ベノワのbluetooth問題 @2021-03-08 20:58:17
 みっきーにうこんをプレゼントした。けいたくんが野菜をくれた。 @2021-03-08 20:56:48
 禅の公案　無とはなにかを間断なく考え続ける @2021-03-08 20:56:14
 IDEA: 輪輪発明事務所　自転車関連の発明品や図面の販売 @2021-03-08 20:54:59 Hello @2021-03-08 20:19:38
 TEST from home dir using alias @2021-03-08 19:52:56
 test test test @2021-03-08 19:47:03
 built new miniblog core @2021-03-08 19:42:21
 worked with keita in the afternoon @2021-03-08 19:39:39
 watched kids in the morning. @2021-03-08 19:39:26)</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 21:01:13 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-03-05</title><description>(discovered ukon to be a great sedative for my body @2021-03-05 22:49:9)</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 22:49:09 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-03-01</title><description>(emailed greenvalley hayashi-kun to look for a house in Kamibun @2021-03-01 22:24:1
 tommorow we go check out the route up the elephant mountain @2021-03-01 21:35:19
 bike to Jinryo and joind kids running club as a staff @2021-03-01 20:22:26
 watched kids in the morning while S is away for yoga class @2021-03-01 20:21:36)</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 22:24:01 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-02-26</title><description>(built sbcl core image for miniblog @2021-02-26 21:40:42
 installed cli audio visualizer @2021-02-26 21:40:21
 went to the library in Itano with fam. bought food on the way home and met mika-san @2021-02-26 21:39:52)</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 21:40:42 +0900</pubDate></item><item><title>2021-02-25</title><description>(上分移住、広野邸山の家計画をsに打ち明けた @2021-02-25 23:30:36
 started writing up a mini blog system in CL @2021-02-25 23:28:36
 剪定withけいたin板野y10k @2021-02-25 23:27:33)</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 23:30:36 +0900</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
